<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:17:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Size of Life</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hi all! I’m Aleix Ramon, the music composer of the soundtrack.&lt;p&gt;Since some of you asked, here’s the soundtrack on Bandcamp: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aleixramon.bandcamp.com&amp;#x2F;album&amp;#x2F;size-of-life-original-soundtrack" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aleixramon.bandcamp.com&amp;#x2F;album&amp;#x2F;size-of-life-original-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;There you can download it in high quality, and it’s a pay-what-you-want: you can get it for free if you want, or pay what you feel like and support me. Either way, I’m happy that you enjoy it!&lt;p&gt;The music should also be on Spotify, Apple Music, and most music streaming services within the next 24h.&lt;p&gt;A bit about the process of scoring Size of Life:&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with Neal before on a couple of his other games, including Absurd Trolley Problems, so we were used to working together (and with his producer—you’re awesome, Liz!). When Neal told me about Size of Life, we had an inspiring conversation about how the music could make the players feel.&lt;p&gt;The core idea was that it should enhance that feeling of wondrous discovery, but subtly, without taking the attention away from the beautiful illustrations.&lt;p&gt;I also thought it should reflect the organisms&amp;#x27; increasing size—as some of you pointed out, the music grows with them. I think of it as a single instrument that builds upon itself, like the cells in an increasingly complex organism. So I composed 12 layers that loop indefinitely—as you progress, each layer is added, and as you go back, they’re subtracted. The effect is most clear if you get to the end and then return to the smaller organisms!&lt;p&gt;Since the game has an encyclopedia vibe to it, I proposed to go with a string instrument to give it a subtle “Enlightenment-era” and “cultural” feel. I was suspecting the cello could be a good instrument because of its range and expressivity.&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, the next week I met the cellist Iratxe Ibaibarriaga at a game conference in Barcelona, where I’m based, and she immediately became the ideal person for it. She’s done a wonderful job bringing a ton of expressivity to the playing, and it’s been a delight to work with her.&lt;p&gt;I got very excited when Neal told me he was making an educational game—I come from a family of school teachers. I’ve been scoring games for over 10 years, but this is the first educational game I’ve scored.&lt;p&gt;In a way, now the circle feels complete!&lt;p&gt;(if anyone wants to reach out, feel free to do so! You can find me and all my stuff here: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aleixramon.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aleixramon.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; )&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://neal.fun/size-of-life/"&gt;neal.fun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>2462</hn_points><hn_author>eatonphil</hn_author><hn_order>32</hn_order></item><item><title>GPT-5.2</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234788</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234788</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:04:47 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;platform.openai.com&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;guides&amp;#x2F;latest-model" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;platform.openai.com&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;guides&amp;#x2F;latest-model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;System card: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;cdn.openai.com&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;3a4153c8-c748-4b71-8e31-aecbde944f8d&amp;#x2F;oai_5_2_system-card.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;cdn.openai.com&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;3a4153c8-c748-4b71-8e31-aecbde944...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have been using chatGPT a ton over the last months and paying the subscription. Used it for coding, news, stock analysis, daily problems, and a whatever I could think of. I decided to give Gemini a go when version three came out to great reviews. Gemini handles every single one of my uses cases much better and consistently gives better answers. This is especially true for situations were searching the web for current information is important, makes sense that google would be better. Also OCR is phenomenal chatgpt can&amp;#x27;t read my bad hand writing but Gemini can easily. Only downsides are in the polish department, there are more app bugs and I usually have to leave the happen or the session terminates. There are bugs with uploading photos. The biggest complaint is that all links get inserted into google search and then I have to manipulate them when they should go directly to the chosen website, this has to be some kind of internal org KPI nonsense. Overall, my conclusion is that ChatGPT has lost and won&amp;#x27;t catch up because of the search integration strength.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2/"&gt;openai.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234788"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>685</hn_points><hn_author>atgctg</hn_author></item><item><title>Auto-grading decade-old Hacker News discussions with hindsight</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:23:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;Related from yesterday: &lt;i&gt;Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 imagines the HN front page 10 years from now&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;#x27;s fun to read some of these historic comments! A while back I wrote a replay system to better capture how discussions evolved at the time of these historic threads. Here&amp;#x27;s Karpathy&amp;#x27;s list from his graded articles, in the replay visualizer:&lt;p&gt;Swift is Open Source
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10669891" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10669891&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launch of Figma, a collaborative interface design tool
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10685407" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10685407&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing OpenAI
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10720176" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10720176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first person to hack the iPhone is building a self-driving car
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10744206" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10744206&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;SpaceX launch webcast: Orbcomm-2 Mission [video]
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10774865" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10774865&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Theranos, Many Strategies and Snags
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10799261" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10799261&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://karpathy.bearblog.dev/auto-grade-hn/"&gt;karpathy.bearblog.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>562</hn_points><hn_author>__rito__</hn_author><hn_order>16</hn_order></item><item><title>iPhone Typos? It's Not Just You – The iOS Keyboard Is Broken [video]</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232528</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232528</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:25:43 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The first iterations of the apple keyboard were perfect. They literally did everything perfectly without any notes.&lt;p&gt;Then it seems like they’re started teaching to the bottoms of the class and added a bunch of terrible decisions: Substituting touch to select instead of touch to move cursor was a genuinely awful decision that now makes typing a constant chore, and it seems like their autocorrect is overcompensating so hard that it prevents me from writing perfectly good words simply because they’re not common ones.&lt;p&gt;Side note: anyone else have moments where you can’t press delete once predictive text has shown up?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hksVvXONrIo"&gt;www.youtube.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232528"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>430</hn_points><hn_author>walterbell</hn_author><hn_order>24</hn_order></item><item><title>The highest quality codebase</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197930</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197930</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:33:09 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Claude is really good at specific analysis, but really terrible at open-ended problems.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hey claude, I get this error message: &amp;lt;X&amp;gt;&amp;quot;, and it&amp;#x27;ll often find the root cause quicker than I could.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hey claude, anything I could do to improve Y?&amp;quot;, and it&amp;#x27;ll struggle beyond the basics that a linter might suggest.&lt;p&gt;It suggested enthusiastically a library for &amp;lt;work domain&amp;gt; and it was all &amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;Recommended&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot; about it, but when I pointed out that the library had been considered and rejected because &amp;lt;issue&amp;gt;, it understood and wrote up why that library suffered from that issue and why it was therefore unsuitable.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a significant blind-spot in current LLMs related to blue-sky thinking and creative problem solving. It can do structured problems very well, and it can transform unstructured data very well, but it can&amp;#x27;t deal with unstructured problems very well.&lt;p&gt;That may well change, so I don&amp;#x27;t want to embed that thought too deeply into my own priors, because the LLM space seems to evolve rapidly. I wouldn&amp;#x27;t want to find myself blind to the progress because I write it off from a class of problems.&lt;p&gt;But right now, the best way to help an LLM is have a deep understanding of the problem domain yourself, and just leverage it to do the grunt-work that you&amp;#x27;d find boring.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://gricha.dev/blog/the-highest-quality-codebase"&gt;gricha.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197930"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>400</hn_points><hn_author>Gricha</hn_author><hn_order>3</hn_order></item><item><title>Booting Linux in QEMU and Writing PID 1 in Go to Illustrate Kernel as Program</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46147987</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46147987</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:25:38 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nice article! One point of clarification:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; When the kernel starts it does not have all of the parts loaded that are needed to access the disks in the computer, so it needs a filesystem loaded into the memory called initramfs (Initial RAM filesystem).&lt;p&gt;The kernel &lt;i&gt;might&lt;/i&gt; not have all the parts needed to mount the filesystem, especially on a modern Linux distro that supports a wide variety of hardware.&lt;p&gt;Initramfs exists so that parts of the boot logic can be handled in userspace. Part of this includes deciding which device drivers to load as kernel modules, using something like udev.&lt;p&gt;Another part is deciding &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; root filesystem to mount. The root FS might be on an LVM volume that needs to be configured with device-mapper, or unlocked with decrypt. Or it might be mounted over a network, which in turn requires IP configuration and authentication. You don&amp;#x27;t want the kernel to have those mechanisms hard-coded, so initramfs allows handling them in userspace.&lt;p&gt;But strictly speaking, you don&amp;#x27;t &lt;i&gt;need&lt;/i&gt; any of that for a minimal system. You can boot without initramfs at all, as long as no special userspace setup is required. i.e., the root FS is a plain old disk partition specified on the kernel command line, and the correct drivers (e.g. for a SCSI&amp;#x2F;SATA hard drive) are already linked into the kernel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://serversfor.dev/linux-inside-out/the-linux-kernel-is-just-a-program/"&gt;serversfor.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46147987"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>253</hn_points><hn_author>birdculture</hn_author><hn_order>36</hn_order></item><item><title>Helldivers 2 on-disk size 85% reduction</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131518</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131518</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:08:31 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The negativity towards this is wild. A company followed relatively widely accepted industry practice (lots and lots of other games also have huge sizes on disk for the exact same reason), then eventually they decided to do their own independent testing to check whether said common practice actually makes things better or not in their case, found that it didn&amp;#x27;t, so they reversed it. In addition, they wrote up some nice technical articles on the topic, helping to change the old accepted industry wisdom.&lt;p&gt;This seems great to me. Am I crazy? This feels like it should be Hacker News&amp;#x27;s bread and butter, articles about &amp;quot;we moved away from Kubernetes&amp;#x2F;microservices&amp;#x2F;node.js&amp;#x2F;serverless&amp;#x2F;React because we did our own investigation and found that the upsides aren&amp;#x27;t worth the downsides&amp;quot; tend to do really well here. How is this received so differently?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/491583942944621371"&gt;store.steampowered.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131518"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>247</hn_points><hn_author>SergeAx</hn_author><hn_order>31</hn_order></item><item><title>UK House of Lords attempting to ban use of VPNs by anyone under 16</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236738</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236738</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:32:22 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On a related note, they built their digital ID so that third parties could verify attributes (it&amp;#x27;s NOT just a single-service login across government + a linking ID across government services, which is how it was sold by the BBC).&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#x27;re pretty close to completely de-anonymising the internet for UK citizens. Say they introduce an Australian-style social media ban for under 16s, then requires all social media to link their accounts to digital IDs for this verification.&lt;p&gt;Naturally the only remaining loophole is if a UK citizen manages to avoid being flagged as British ever by using a VPN, so I expect they will focus on that going forwards. Keep in mind the UK already arrests and imprisons vast numbers of people for speech offences, there&amp;#x27;s no slippery-slope argument here because the UK is already at the bottom of the slope as an ultra-authoratitarian anti-speech nation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://alecmuffett.com/article/134925"&gt;alecmuffett.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236738"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>226</hn_points><hn_author>nvarsj</hn_author><hn_order>9</hn_order></item><item><title>Craft software that makes people feel something</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231274</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231274</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:45:08 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;gt; created solely for myself; I never had the intention of making it [...] mainstream&lt;p&gt;This is how many artists have worked. They make something for themself, and one day they show it to someone else ... or they just get the urge to share it more widely, often without the hope that anyone will really be interested. Or they keep it for themself.&lt;p&gt;I think Tolkien is in that group, for example. But don&amp;#x27;t get the wrong idea from an extreme outlier: much of the time, others aren&amp;#x27;t interested, or not many are. Sometimes, nobody is interested until after you&amp;#x27;ve forgotten about it or passed away. Who cares? That&amp;#x27;s one reason you need to make it for yourself. Also, I think that otherwise it provides much less expression and insight into another person, which is at the core of art. There is a fundamental human need to &amp;#x27;externalize the imagination&amp;#x27;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://rapha.land/craft-software-that-makes-people-feel-something/"&gt;rapha.land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231274"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>223</hn_points><hn_author>lukeio</hn_author><hn_order>10</hn_order></item><item><title>Litestream VFS</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234710</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234710</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 17:59:10 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh hey this is using my go sqlite vfs module[0]. I love it when I find out some code I wrote is useful to others!&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;psanford&amp;#x2F;sqlite3vfs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;psanford&amp;#x2F;sqlite3vfs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://fly.io/blog/litestream-vfs/"&gt;fly.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234710"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>205</hn_points><hn_author>emschwartz</hn_author><hn_order>5</hn_order></item><item><title>EFF launches Age Verification Hub</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223389</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223389</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:35:07 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;Also: We built a resource hub to fight back against age verification &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.eff.org&amp;#x2F;deeplinks&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;12&amp;#x2F;age-verification-coming-internet-we-built-you-resource-hub-fight-back" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.eff.org&amp;#x2F;deeplinks&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;12&amp;#x2F;age-verification-comin...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This keeps coming up and we keep having the same debates about what Age Verification isn&amp;#x27;t.&lt;p&gt;For the folks in the back row:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Age Verification isn&amp;#x27;t about Kids or Censorship, It&amp;#x27;s about Surveillance&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Age Verification isn&amp;#x27;t about Kids or Censorship, It&amp;#x27;s about Surveillance&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Age Verification isn&amp;#x27;t about Kids or Censorship, It&amp;#x27;s about Surveillance&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without even reaching for my tinfoil hat, the strategy at work here is clear [0 1 2].  If we have to know that you&amp;#x27;re not a minor, then we also have to know who you are so we can make any techniques to obfuscate that illegal.  By turning this from &amp;quot;keep an eye on your kids&amp;quot; to &amp;quot;prove you&amp;#x27;re not a kid&amp;quot; they&amp;#x27;ve created the conditions to make privacy itself illegal.&lt;p&gt;VPNs are next.  Then PGP.  Then anything else that makes it hard for them to know who you are, what you say, and who you say it to.&lt;p&gt;Please, please don&amp;#x27;t fall into the trap and start discussing whether or not this is going to be effective to protect kids.  It isn&amp;#x27;t, and that isn&amp;#x27;t the point.&lt;p&gt;0 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.eff.org&amp;#x2F;deeplinks&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;lawmakers-want-ban-vpns-and-they-have-no-idea-what-theyre-doing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.eff.org&amp;#x2F;deeplinks&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;lawmakers-want-ban-vpn...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;1 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.techradar.com&amp;#x2F;vpn&amp;#x2F;vpn-privacy-security&amp;#x2F;vpn-usage-at-risk-in-michigan-under-new-proposed-adult-content-law" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.techradar.com&amp;#x2F;vpn&amp;#x2F;vpn-privacy-security&amp;#x2F;vpn-usage...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hansard.parliament.uk&amp;#x2F;Lords&amp;#x2F;2025-09-15&amp;#x2F;debates&amp;#x2F;57714CE6-0CE4-49F6-B028-E271D5100F7F&amp;#x2F;OnlineSafetyAct2023VirtualPrivateNetworks" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hansard.parliament.uk&amp;#x2F;Lords&amp;#x2F;2025-09-15&amp;#x2F;debates&amp;#x2F;57714...&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/press/releases/eff-launches-age-verification-hub-resource-against-misguided-laws"&gt;www.eff.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223389"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>205</hn_points><hn_author>iamnothere</hn_author><hn_order>25</hn_order></item><item><title>French supermarket's Christmas advert is worldwide hit (without AI) [video]</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231187</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231187</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:35:55 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;OP is the original upload, but the agency reposted it with English subs after it got popular outside of France: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=iLERt5ZkpQ4" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=iLERt5ZkpQ4&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Na9VmMNJvsA"&gt;www.youtube.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231187"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>192</hn_points><hn_author>gbugniot</hn_author><hn_order>23</hn_order></item><item><title>Rivian Unveils Custom Silicon, R2 Lidar Roadmap, and Universal Hands Free</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234920</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234920</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:17:19 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Autonomy subscriptions are how things are going to go, I called this a long time ago. It makes too much sense in terms of continuous development and operations&amp;#x2F;support to not have a subscription -- and subscriptions will likely double as insurance at some point in the future (once the car is driving itself 100% of the time, and liability is always with the self driving stack anyway).&lt;p&gt;Of course, people won&amp;#x27;t like this, I&amp;#x27;m not exactly enthused either, but the alternative would be a corporation constantly providing -- for free -- updates and even support if your car gets into an accident or stuck. That doesn&amp;#x27;t really make sense from a business perspective.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://riviantrackr.com/news/rivian-unveils-custom-silicon-r2-lidar-roadmap-universal-hands-free-and-its-next-gen-autonomy-platform/"&gt;riviantrackr.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234920"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>182</hn_points><hn_author>doctoboggan</hn_author><hn_order>2</hn_order></item><item><title>The Cost of a Closure in C</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46228597</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46228597</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 07:21:33 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;It’s no wonder GCC is trying to add -ftrampoline-impl=heap to the story of GNU Nested Functions; they might be able to tighten up that performance and make it more competitive with Apple Blocks.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;[disclaimer] Without brushing up on the details of this, I strongly suspect that this is about removing the need for executable stacks than performance. Allocating a trampoline on the stack rather than heap is &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; for efficiency.&lt;p&gt;These days, many GNU&amp;#x2F;Linux distros are disabling executable stacks by default in their toolchain configuration, both for building the distro and for the toolchain offered &lt;i&gt;by&lt;/i&gt; the system to the user.&lt;p&gt;When you use GCC local functions, it overrides the linker behavior so that the executable is marked for executable stacks.&lt;p&gt;Of course, that is a security concession because when your stack is executable, that enables malicious remote execution code to work that relies on injecting code into the stack via a buffer overflow and tricking the process into jumping to it.&lt;p&gt;If trampolines can be allocated in a heap, then you don&amp;#x27;t need an executable stack. You do need an executable heap, or an executable dedicated heap for these allocations. (Trampolines are all the same size, so they could be packed into an array.)&lt;p&gt;Programs which indirect upon GCC local functions are not aware of the trampolines. The trampolines are deallocated naturally when the stack rolls back on function return or longjmp, or a C++ exception passing through.&lt;p&gt;Heap-allocated trampolines have an obvious deallocation problem; it would be interesting to see what strategy is used for that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://thephd.dev/the-cost-of-a-closure-in-c-c2y"&gt;thephd.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46228597"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>182</hn_points><hn_author>ingve</hn_author><hn_order>33</hn_order></item><item><title>A “frozen” dictionary for Python</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46229467</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46229467</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 09:51:47 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wonder whether Raymond Hettinger has an opinion on this PEP. A long time ago, he wrote: &amp;quot;freezing dicts is a can of worms and not especially useful&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mail.python.org&amp;#x2F;pipermail&amp;#x2F;python-dev&amp;#x2F;2006-February&amp;#x2F;060793.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mail.python.org&amp;#x2F;pipermail&amp;#x2F;python-dev&amp;#x2F;2006-February&amp;#x2F;0...&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/1047238/25c270b077849dc0/"&gt;lwn.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46229467"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>180</hn_points><hn_author>jwilk</hn_author><hn_order>39</hn_order></item></channel></rss>