<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:05:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Size of Life</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hi all! I’m Aleix Ramon, the music composer of the soundtrack.&lt;p&gt;Since some of you asked, here’s the soundtrack on Bandcamp: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aleixramon.bandcamp.com&amp;#x2F;album&amp;#x2F;size-of-life-original-soundtrack" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aleixramon.bandcamp.com&amp;#x2F;album&amp;#x2F;size-of-life-original-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;There you can download it in high quality, and it’s a pay-what-you-want: you can get it for free if you want, or pay what you feel like and support me. Either way, I’m happy that you enjoy it!&lt;p&gt;The music should also be on Spotify, Apple Music, and most music streaming services within the next 24h.&lt;p&gt;A bit about the process of scoring Size of Life:&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with Neal before on a couple of his other games, including Absurd Trolley Problems, so we were used to working together (and with his producer—you’re awesome, Liz!). When Neal told me about Size of Life, we had an inspiring conversation about how the music could make the players feel.&lt;p&gt;The core idea was that it should enhance that feeling of wondrous discovery, but subtly, without taking the attention away from the beautiful illustrations.&lt;p&gt;I also thought it should reflect the organisms&amp;#x27; increasing size—as some of you pointed out, the music grows with them. I think of it as a single instrument that builds upon itself, like the cells in an increasingly complex organism. So I composed 12 layers that loop indefinitely—as you progress, each layer is added, and as you go back, they’re subtracted. The effect is most clear if you get to the end and then return to the smaller organisms!&lt;p&gt;Since the game has an encyclopedia vibe to it, I proposed to go with a string instrument to give it a subtle “Enlightenment-era” and “cultural” feel. I was suspecting the cello could be a good instrument because of its range and expressivity.&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, the next week I met the cellist Iratxe Ibaibarriaga at a game conference in Barcelona, where I’m based, and she immediately became the ideal person for it. She’s done a wonderful job bringing a ton of expressivity to the playing, and it’s been a delight to work with her.&lt;p&gt;I got very excited when Neal told me he was making an educational game—I come from a family of school teachers. I’ve been scoring games for over 10 years, but this is the first educational game I’ve scored.&lt;p&gt;In a way, now the circle feels complete!&lt;p&gt;(if anyone wants to reach out, feel free to do so! You can find me and all my stuff here: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aleixramon.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aleixramon.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; )&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://neal.fun/size-of-life/"&gt;neal.fun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>2262</hn_points><hn_author>eatonphil</hn_author><hn_order>2</hn_order></item><item><title>Australia begins enforcing world-first teen social media ban</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46208348</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46208348</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:12:29 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.md&amp;#x2F;i0VxX" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.md&amp;#x2F;i0VxX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.bbc.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;live&amp;#x2F;cwy54q80gy9t" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.bbc.com&amp;#x2F;news&amp;#x2F;live&amp;#x2F;cwy54q80gy9t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nytimes.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;12&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;world&amp;#x2F;asia&amp;#x2F;australia-social-media-ban-under-16.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nytimes.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;12&amp;#x2F;09&amp;#x2F;world&amp;#x2F;asia&amp;#x2F;australia-soci...&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;Ba2JR" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;Ba2JR&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was in college when this really cool idea came out: a social network database which &lt;i&gt;only college students could join&lt;/i&gt;, regulating access to students@*.edu emails, only [obviously: TheFaceBook].&lt;p&gt;Seems like local school districts could reintroduce such a platform (perhaps one already exists) for class discussions to continue outside of the classroom... but without the temptations of the outside world [which these u16 bans rightfully seek to limit]. Hyper-walled gardens, actual community-based social spaces.&lt;p&gt;As always, I imagine with the unlimited timelessness of childhood multiple clever work-arounds will persist, regardless of any law. May the cat-and-mouse be merry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/litigation/australia-social-media-ban-takes-effect-world-first-2025-12-09/"&gt;www.reuters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46208348"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>874</hn_points><hn_author>chirau</hn_author><hn_order>6</hn_order></item><item><title>Valve: HDMI Forum Continues to Block HDMI 2.1 for Linux</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220488</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220488</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:20:06 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Standard link to download: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dokumen.pub&amp;#x2F;download&amp;#x2F;hdmi-specification-21-high-definition-multimedia-interface-specification-v21-v21nbsped.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dokumen.pub&amp;#x2F;download&amp;#x2F;hdmi-specification-21-high-defi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alternative: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;annas-archive.org&amp;#x2F;md5&amp;#x2F;4dd395c749519a36cb755e6ebbe48847" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;annas-archive.org&amp;#x2F;md5&amp;#x2F;4dd395c749519a36cb755e6ebbe488...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alternative (incomplete, only couple first page):  &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;device.report&amp;#x2F;m&amp;#x2F;91235972e8cbf6d6ce84f7cf84ca0ac12623463530d1f80560f22b47b9ba9858" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;device.report&amp;#x2F;m&amp;#x2F;91235972e8cbf6d6ce84f7cf84ca0ac12623...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other HDMI stuff: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pdfhost.io&amp;#x2F;v&amp;#x2F;YidEvBDkS_EP92A7E_EP91A7E_DS_V04" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;pdfhost.io&amp;#x2F;v&amp;#x2F;YidEvBDkS_EP92A7E_EP91A7E_DS_V04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Older available here: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;glenwing.github.io&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;glenwing.github.io&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.heise.de/en/news/Valve-HDMI-Forum-Continues-to-Block-HDMI-2-1-for-Linux-11107440.html"&gt;www.heise.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220488"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>810</hn_points><hn_author>OsrsNeedsf2P</hn_author><hn_order>34</hn_order></item><item><title>Bruno Simon – 3D Portfolio</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206531</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206531</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:06:58 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For those that can&amp;#x27;t get it to load (it takes a minute, and I noticed my desktop&amp;#x27;s fan kick it up a notch while things were getting initialized, so... YMMV): this is a portfolio site done via a cozy-gaming-style AWSD game where you drive around in a jeep-like thingamabob. There are some cute easter eggs, including a sort of... shrine to each of the socials, which you can run into with your car and knock over (though the links remain clickable, of course!). It also looks like there&amp;#x27;s some degree of global state; for example, you can &amp;quot;sacrifice yourself to the gods of chaos&amp;quot; (ie drive into a portal) and a counter on the side of the portal goes up, presumably for everyone (since I certainly didn&amp;#x27;t drive into it 1700 times myself!). There&amp;#x27;s a strongly consistent art style, and just generally... seems pretty polished. Or at least, that&amp;#x27;s what it felt like after 5 minutes of driving around.&lt;p&gt;All in all I&amp;#x27;d say, I&amp;#x27;m impressed, and enjoyed it. Though I think the HN title (&amp;quot;handsdown one of the coolest 3D websites&amp;quot;) is maybe a bit much. It&amp;#x27;s an extremely-well-executed portfolio site; no more, no less.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://bruno-simon.com/"&gt;bruno-simon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206531"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>756</hn_points><hn_author>razzmataks</hn_author><hn_order>43</hn_order></item><item><title>Getting a Gemini API key is an exercise in frustration</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223311</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223311</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:29:12 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was recently (vibe)-coding some games with my kid, and we wanted some basic text-to-speech functionality. We tested Google&amp;#x27;s Gemini models in-browser, and they worked great, so we figured we&amp;#x27;d add them to the app. Some fun learnings:&lt;p&gt;1. You can access those models via three APIs: the Gemini API (which it turns out is only for prototyping and returned errors 30% of the time), the Vertex API (much more stable but lacking in some functionality), and the TTS API (which performed very poorly despite offering the same models). They also have separate keys (at least, Gemini vs Vertex).&lt;p&gt;2. Each of those APIs supports different parameters (things like language, whether you can pass a style prompt separate from the words you want spoken, etc). None of them offered the full combination we wanted.&lt;p&gt;3. To learn this, you have to spend a couple hours reading API docs, or alternatively, just have Claude Code read the docs then try all different combinations and figure out what works and what doesn&amp;#x27;t (with the added risk that it might hallucinate something).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://ankursethi.com/blog/gemini-api-key-frustration/"&gt;ankursethi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223311"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>661</hn_points><hn_author>speckx</hn_author><hn_order>5</hn_order></item><item><title>Auto-grading decade-old Hacker News discussions with hindsight</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:23:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;Related from yesterday: &lt;i&gt;Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 imagines the HN front page 10 years from now&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It doesn&amp;#x27;t look like the code anonymizes usernames when sending the thread for grading. This likely induces bias in the grades based on past&amp;#x2F;current prevailing opinions of certain users. It would be interesting to see the whole thing done again but this time randomly re-assigning usernames, to assess bias, and also with procedurally generated pseudonyms, to see whether the bias can be removed that way.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;d expect de-biasing would deflate grades for well known users.&lt;p&gt;It might also be interesting to use a search-grounded model that provides citations for its grading claims. Gemini models have access to this via their API, for example.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://karpathy.bearblog.dev/auto-grade-hn/"&gt;karpathy.bearblog.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>488</hn_points><hn_author>__rito__</hn_author><hn_order>16</hn_order></item><item><title>Patterns.dev</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226483</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226483</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:18:55 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Design patterns can be really helpful. In my previous job I worked on enterprise .NET applications. It made sense to use common patterns, because most applications were big and the patterns made it easier to understand unfamiliar code, within an application but also across different teams and applications. New projects looked familiar, because the same style and the same patterns were used.&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#x27;m working on an old (+10 years) JS application. Similar patterns were implemented, but in this case it&amp;#x27;s not helpful at all. The code looks very corporate and Java EE style, with a ton of getters and setters (`getName() {}`, not `get name() {}`, factories, facades, adapters, etc, etc. It&amp;#x27;s usually completely unclear what the benefit of the pattern is, and code is more complicated, for instance because creating new instances of business objects is split into `Object.build` which calls `new Object`, with no guidelines at all what part of the initialization should be in `build` and what should be in the constructor.&lt;p&gt;The gist of my comment is that patterns can be useful, but usually they&amp;#x27;re overused and if you implement one without understanding why and without benefiting from faster understanding the code because the pattern is applied consistently over multiple instances, the result is worse than just implementing what you need in a readable way (YAGNI).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.patterns.dev/"&gt;www.patterns.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226483"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>406</hn_points><hn_author>handfuloflight</hn_author><hn_order>7</hn_order></item><item><title>Rubio stages font coup: Times New Roman ousts Calibri</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212438</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212438</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:08:34 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.md&amp;#x2F;x0Sxc" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.md&amp;#x2F;x0Sxc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our studio, LucasFonts, designed Calibri. Here are our CEO Luc(as) de Groot’s thoughts on the matter:&lt;p&gt;The decision to abandon Calibri on the grounds of it being a so-called “wasteful diversity font” is both amusing and regrettable. Calibri was specifically designed to enhance readability on modern computer screens and was selected by Microsoft in 2007 to replace Times New Roman as the default font in the Office suite. There were sound reasons for moving away from Times: Calibri performs exceptionally well at small sizes and on standard office monitors, whereas serif fonts like Times New Roman tend to appear more distorted. While serif fonts are well-suited to high-resolution displays, such as those found on modern smartphones, on typical office screens the serifs introduce unnecessary visual noise and can be particularly problematic for users with impaired vision, such as older adults.&lt;p&gt;Professional typography can be achieved with both serif and sans-serif fonts. However, Times New Roman—a typeface older than the current president—presents unique challenges. Originally crafted in Great Britain for newspaper printing, Times was optimised for paper, with each letterform meticulously cut and tested for specific sizes. In the digital era, larger size drawings were repurposed as models, resulting in a typeface that appears too thin and sharp when printed at high quality.&lt;p&gt;Serif fonts are often perceived as more traditional, but they are also more demanding to use effectively. While a skilled typographer can, in theory, produce excellent results with Times, using it in its default digital form is not considered professional practice.&lt;p&gt;Calibri, by contrast, incorporates extensive spacing adjustments and language-specific refinements. The digital version of Times New Roman, developed in the early days of computing, offers only minimal kerning and letter-pair adjustments. This is especially evident in words set in all capitals—such as “CHICAGO”—where the spacing is inconsistent: the letters “HIC” are tightly packed, while “CAG” are spaced too far apart. Microsoft cannot rectify these issues without altering the appearance of existing documents.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/rubio-stages-font-coup-times-new-roman-ousts-calibri-2025-12-09/"&gt;www.reuters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212438"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>338</hn_points><hn_author>italophil</hn_author><hn_order>23</hn_order></item><item><title>How Google Maps allocates survival across London's restaurants</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203343</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203343</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:20:02 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;#x27;s always annoyed me that zooming in on a building will not reliably show the business that operates there. I understand that at low zoom levels you may need to filter what is displayed based on the high density, but when I zoom in I want to see everything that is there. Sometimes I am forced to go to street view to read the sign, then type the company name into the search box to force the business marker to show up and get clickable.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve found Apple Maps is a little better in this regard. They show a higher density of business markers at any given zoom level.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://laurenleek.substack.com/p/how-google-maps-quietly-allocates"&gt;laurenleek.substack.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203343"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>324</hn_points><hn_author>justincormack</hn_author><hn_order>20</hn_order></item><item><title>Qwen3-Omni-Flash-2025-12-01：a next-generation native multimodal large model</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219538</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219538</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:13:38 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is a 30B parameter MoE with 3B active parameters and is the successor to their previous 7B omni model. [1]&lt;p&gt;You can expect this model to have similar performance to the non-omni version. [2]&lt;p&gt;There aren&amp;#x27;t many open-weights omni models so I consider this a big deal. I would use this model to replace the keyboard and monitor in an application while doing the heavy lifting with other tech behind the scenes. There is also a reasoning version, which might be a bit amusing in an interactive voice chat if it pronounces the thinking tokens while working through to a final answer.&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;huggingface.co&amp;#x2F;Qwen&amp;#x2F;Qwen2.5-Omni-7B" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;huggingface.co&amp;#x2F;Qwen&amp;#x2F;Qwen2.5-Omni-7B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;artificialanalysis.ai&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;qwen3-30b-a3b-instruct" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;artificialanalysis.ai&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;qwen3-30b-a3b-instruct&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://qwen.ai/blog?id=qwen3-omni-flash-20251201"&gt;qwen.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219538"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>288</hn_points><hn_author>pretext</hn_author><hn_order>27</hn_order></item><item><title>Super Mario 64 for the PS1</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221925</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221925</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you like this port, you may also enjoy this ground-up effort to clone SM64 on the GBA &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;nS5rj80L-pk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;nS5rj80L-pk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/malucard/sm64-psx"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221925"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>266</hn_points><hn_author>LaserDiscMan</hn_author><hn_order>24</hn_order></item><item><title>Is it a bubble?</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220640</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220640</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:30:43 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;gt; In many advanced software teams, developers no longer write the code; they type in what they want, and AI systems generate the code for them.&lt;p&gt;What a wild and speculative claim. Is there any source for this information?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.oaktreecapital.com/insights/memo/is-it-a-bubble"&gt;www.oaktreecapital.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220640"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>264</hn_points><hn_author>saigrandhi</hn_author><hn_order>38</hn_order></item><item><title>Gundam is just the same as Jane Austen but happens to include giant mech suits</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123310</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123310</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 16:55:36 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;quot;It is a truth universally acknowledged that a single man in possession of a good fortune must be in want of a robot suit to ride around and fight things with.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;I was visiting Jane Austen&amp;#x27;s House Museum last year and it always gives me pleasure to see how wildly popular her work remains. There always seem to be tourists there visiting from all over the world. That is really heartening.&lt;p&gt;She was very innovative. Maybe even underrated as a craftsperson at the sentence level. My favourite trick that I believe she invented is slipping from prose into a soft Iambic pentameter, essentially unnoticed. Lots of people have copied that from her.&lt;p&gt;And class-pressure narratives will never not be relevant to people&amp;#x27;s lives. She&amp;#x27;s a very very humane storyteller in that respect.&lt;p&gt;I am slightly biased - she&amp;#x27;s my great aunt (x 6). Used to find that embarrassing but now I feel quite proud.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://eli.li/gundam-is-just-the-same-as-jane-austen-but-happens-to-include-giant-mech-suits"&gt;eli.li&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123310"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>231</hn_points><hn_author>surprisetalk</hn_author><hn_order>40</hn_order></item><item><title>Show HN: Automated license plate reader coverage in the USA</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220794</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220794</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:42:30 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;Built this over the last few days, based on a Rust codebase that parses the latest ALPR reports from OpenStreetMaps, calculates navigation statistics from every tagged residential building to nearby amenities, and tests each route for intersection with those ALPR cameras (Flock being the most widespread).&lt;p&gt;These have gotten more controversial in recent months, due to their indiscriminate large scale data collection, with 404 Media publishing many original pieces (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.404media.co&amp;#x2F;tag&amp;#x2F;flock&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.404media.co&amp;#x2F;tag&amp;#x2F;flock&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) about their adoption and (ab)use across the country. I wanted to use open source datasets to track the rapid expansion, especially per-county, as this data can be crucial for &amp;#x27;deflock&amp;#x27; movements to petition counties and city governments to ban and remove them.&lt;p&gt;In some counties, the tracking becomes so widespread that most people can&amp;#x27;t go anywhere without being photographed. This includes possibly sensitive areas, like places of worship and medical facilities.&lt;p&gt;The argument for their legality rests upon the notion that these cameras are equivalent to &amp;#x27;mere observation&amp;#x27;, but the enormous scope and data sharing agreements in place to share and access &lt;i&gt;millions&lt;/i&gt; of records without warrants blurs the lines of the fourth amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#x27;ve thought about this a lot as I see more and more reckless driving in the areas I live in. Surveillance is generally a net negative, but it&amp;#x27;s also bad when you see people speeding around schools, rolling through stop signs, and running red lights. We seem to have a worst of all situations where traffic is getting increasingly difficult to enforce, driving is getting more dangerous year by year, and we&amp;#x27;re terrified of government overreach if we add any automation at all to enforcement.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t know the solution, but I do know that in the US we&amp;#x27;ve lost 10-15 years of progress when it comes to traffic fatalities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://alpranalysis.com"&gt;alpranalysis.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220794"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>210</hn_points><hn_author>sodality2</hn_author><hn_order>29</hn_order></item><item><title>Vibe coding is mad depressing</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46227422</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46227422</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 03:50:04 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This article is not about vibe coding per se, it&amp;#x27;s about not having strong boundaries between you as the developer, and your client. You should not be allowing the client to dictate how you work, much less them having the permissions to merge in code. This was true before AI too, where clients might say, do X this way, and you should simply say no, because they are paying for &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; expertise*. It&amp;#x27;s like hiring a plumber then trying to tell them how to fix the toilet.&lt;p&gt;*as an aside, this reminds me of the classic joke where the client asks for the price list for a developer&amp;#x27;s services:&lt;p&gt;I do it: $500&lt;p&gt;I do it, but you watch: $750&lt;p&gt;I do it, and you help: $1,000&lt;p&gt;You do it yourself: $5,000&lt;p&gt;You start it, and you want me to finish it: $10,000&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://law.gmnz.xyz/vibe-coding-is-mad-depressing/"&gt;law.gmnz.xyz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46227422"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>201</hn_points><hn_author>dirtylowprofile</hn_author><hn_order>39</hn_order></item></channel></rss>