<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:06:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Linux Sandboxes and Fil-C</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259064</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259064</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 22:58:29 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://fil-c.org/seccomp"&gt;fil-c.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a hybrid approach of C -&amp;gt; WASM -&amp;gt; C compilation, which ends up controlling every OS interaction and sandboxing memory access like WASM, while technically remaining C code:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rlbox.dev&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rlbox.dev&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 335 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; pizlonator&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259064"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>335</hn_points><hn_author>pizlonator</hn_author><hn_order>52</hn_order></item><item><title>Hashcards: A plain-text spaced repetition system</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264492</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264492</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:55:29 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://borretti.me/article/hashcards-plain-text-spaced-repetition"&gt;borretti.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I think that the real power of spaced repetition is not in flashcard applications like this. It is in behavior modification.&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#x27;s take a real example to show how this works.&lt;p&gt;August 19, 2025. My wife called me in to help her decide what to do about a dentist that she thought was ripping her off. A couple of quick suggestions later, and she went to being mad at me about not having heard the problem through before trying to fix it badly. As soon as she was mad, I immediately connected with how stupid what I did was, and that this never goes well. But, of course, it was now too late.&lt;p&gt;Not a mistake I was going to make for a while. But, given my history, a mistake I was bound to make again.&lt;p&gt;I changed that. This time I stuck this into my spaced repetition system. Each time the prompt comes up, I remember that scene, holding in mind how it important it is to emotionally engage, not offer quick suggestions, and be sure to listen to the full problem in detail. It takes me less than 30 seconds. Reviewing this prompt, for my whole lifetime, will take less than 15 minutes of work.  Just typing this up this time takes more work than I&amp;#x27;ll spend on it in the next several years.&lt;p&gt;This mistake hasn&amp;#x27;t happened since. Not once. And I believe it won&amp;#x27;t again in my life.&lt;p&gt;I have literally changed dozens of such behaviors. My wife says that it is like there is a whole new me. She can&amp;#x27;t believe the transformation.&lt;p&gt;All it took is looking at spaced repetition as general purpose structured reinforcement, and not as just a way to study flashcards.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 325 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; thomascountz&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264492"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>325</hn_points><hn_author>thomascountz</hn_author><hn_order>15</hn_order></item><item><title>Elevated errors across many models</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46267385</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46267385</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 21:53:13 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://status.claude.com/incidents/9g6qpr72ttbr"&gt;status.claude.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Props to them for actually updating their status page as issues are happening rather than hours later. I was working with claude code and hit an API error, checked the status page and sure enough there was an outage.&lt;p&gt;This should be a given for any service that others rely on, but sadly this is seldom the case.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 298 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; pablo24602&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46267385"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>298</hn_points><hn_author>pablo24602</hn_author><hn_order>20</hn_order></item><item><title>Ask HN: What Are You Working On? (December 2025)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264491</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264491</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:55:25 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264491"&gt;news.ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are you working on?  Any new ideas that you&amp;#x27;re thinking about?&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mytinycafe.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mytinycafe.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;An PWA primarily for my wife and my daughter. They can order their hot chocolate and their coffee as if they were going to grab something at a fancy café downtown, but instead it&amp;#x27;s at home and I&amp;#x27;m the barista. It is quite nice to have for when my wife comes back from work and want something specific, or when we are waiting for the visit of a few friend, they can order exactly the available beverages and everything is ready when they&amp;#x27;re here.&lt;p&gt;It was also a good playground for me to implement Web Push notifications (to never miss new orders).&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s a basic Nuxt 3 app with Appwrite as the backend with rough edges, but much enough for our household use !&lt;p&gt;If you want to spam my phone with notifications, please visit my café : &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mytinycafe.com&amp;#x2F;alix" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;mytinycafe.com&amp;#x2F;alix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 279 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; david927&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264491"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>279</hn_points><hn_author>david927</hn_author><hn_order>3</hn_order></item><item><title>AI and the ironies of automation – Part 2</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262816</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262816</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:19:15 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.ufried.com/blog/ironies_of_ai_2/"&gt;www.ufried.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I really like this author&amp;#x27;s summary of the 1983 Bainbridge paper about industrial automation. I have often wondered how to apply those insights to AI agents, but I was never able to summarize it as well as OP.&lt;p&gt;Bainbridge by itself is a tough paper to read because it&amp;#x27;s so dense. It&amp;#x27;s just four pages long and worth following along:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ckrybus.com&amp;#x2F;static&amp;#x2F;papers&amp;#x2F;Bainbridge_1983_Automatica.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;ckrybus.com&amp;#x2F;static&amp;#x2F;papers&amp;#x2F;Bainbridge_1983_Automatica...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, see this statement in the paper: &amp;quot;the present generation of automated systems, which are monitored by former manual operators, are riding on their skills, which later generations of operators cannot be expected to have.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;This summarizes the first irony of automation, which is now familiar to everyone on HN: using AI agents effectively requires an expert programmer, but to build the skills to be an expert programmer, you have to program yourself.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s full of insights like that. Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 234 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; BinaryIgor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262816"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>234</hn_points><hn_author>BinaryIgor</hn_author><hn_order>33</hn_order></item><item><title>Shai-Hulud compromised a dev machine and raided GitHub org access: a post-mortem</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262021</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262021</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:07:00 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://trigger.dev/blog/shai-hulud-postmortem"&gt;trigger.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;Running npm install is not negligence. Installing dependencies is not a security failure. The security failure is in an ecosystem that allows packages to run arbitrary code silently.&lt;p&gt;No, your security failure is that you use a package manager that allows third-parties push arbitrary code into your product with no oversight.  You only have &amp;quot;secutity&amp;quot; to the extent that you can trust the people who control those packages to act both competently and in good faith ad infinitum.&lt;p&gt;Also the OP seemingly implies credentials are stored on-filesystem in plaintext but I might be extrapolating too much there.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 228 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; nkko&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262021"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>228</hn_points><hn_author>nkko</hn_author><hn_order>28</hn_order></item><item><title>GraphQL: The enterprise honeymoon is over</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264704</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264704</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 17:13:30 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://johnjames.blog/posts/graphql-the-enterprise-honeymoon-is-over"&gt;johnjames.blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The main problem GraphQL tries to solve is overfetching.&lt;p&gt;My issue with this article is that, as someone who is a GraphQL fan, that is &lt;i&gt;far&lt;/i&gt; from what I see as its primary benefit, and so the rest of the article feels like a strawman to me.&lt;p&gt;TBH I see the biggest benefits of GraphQL are that it (a) forces a &lt;i&gt;much&lt;/i&gt; tighter contract around endpoint and object definition with its type system, and (b) schema evolution is much easier than in other API tech.&lt;p&gt;For the first point, the entire ecosystem &lt;i&gt;guarantees&lt;/i&gt; that when a server receives an input object, that object will conform to the type, and similarly, a client receiving a return object is guaranteed to conform to the endpoint response type. Coupled with custom scalar types (e.g. &amp;quot;phone number&amp;quot; types, &amp;quot;email address&amp;quot; types), this can eliminate a whole class of bugs and security issues. Yes, other API tech does something similar, but I find the guarantees are far less &amp;quot;guaranteed&amp;quot; and it&amp;#x27;s much easier to have errors slip through. Like GraphQL always prunes return objects to just the fields requested, which most other API tech &lt;i&gt;doesn&amp;#x27;t&lt;/i&gt; do, and this can be a really nice security benefit.&lt;p&gt;When it comes to schema evolution, I&amp;#x27;ve found that adding new fields and deprecating old ones, and &lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; that new clients only ever have to be concerned with the new fields, is a huge benefit. Again, other API tech &lt;i&gt;allows&lt;/i&gt; you to do something like this, but it&amp;#x27;s much less standardized and requires a lot more work and cognitive load on both the server and client devs.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 228 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; johnjames4214&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264704"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>228</hn_points><hn_author>johnjames4214</hn_author><hn_order>36</hn_order></item><item><title>Kimi K2 1T model runs on 2 512GB M3 Ultras</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262734</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262734</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:04:34 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/awnihannun/status/1943723599971443134"&gt;twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Kimi K2 is a really weird model, just in general.&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s not nearly as smart as Opus 4.5 or 5.2-Pro or whatever, but it has a &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; distinct writing style and also a much more direct &amp;quot;interpersonal&amp;quot; style.  As a writer of very-short-form stuff like emails, it&amp;#x27;s probably the best model available right now.  As a chatbot, it&amp;#x27;s the only one that seems to really relish calling you out on mistakes or nonsense, and it doesn&amp;#x27;t hesitate to be blunt with you.&lt;p&gt;I get the feeling that it was trained &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; differently from the other models, which makes it situationally useful even if it&amp;#x27;s not very good for data analysis or working through complex questions.  For instance, as it&amp;#x27;s both a good prose stylist and very direct&amp;#x2F;blunt, it&amp;#x27;s an &lt;i&gt;extremely&lt;/i&gt; good editor.&lt;p&gt;I like it enough that I actually pay for a Kimi subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 218 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; jeudesprits&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262734"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>218</hn_points><hn_author>jeudesprits</hn_author><hn_order>56</hn_order></item><item><title>Developing a food-safe finish for my wooden spoons</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224303</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224303</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:44:30 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://alinpanaitiu.com/blog/developing-hardwax-oil/"&gt;alinpanaitiu.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I treat the spoons and ladles I carve with food grade organic flax&amp;#x2F;linseed oil and roast in a fan oven at 180 deg C, giving a robust coating that is also very safe. A few coats are required to fill all the pores in the wood for a beautiful satin finish but all the coats can be completed in a couple of hours total. Colours start at a something slightly darker than the natural oil colour and darken to the colour of chocolate depending on how long they’re in the oven for. The smell is of hot cooking oil unless you go for full chocolate brown in which case it starts to smell of burnt oil and a bit smoky. Fully dry your item first and heat it up slowly in the oven to 180 deg C before applying the first coat so that all areas cure and colour equally. Saturate the wood initially then wipe off all excess with a paper towel which you can then use to add the subsequent coats. Check on the spoon and remove any drips that appear during roasting before they harden. Silicone oven mitts are great for handling the spoons while hot.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 197 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; alin23&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224303"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>197</hn_points><hn_author>alin23</hn_author><hn_order>35</hn_order></item><item><title>2002: Last.fm and Audioscrobbler Herald the Social Web</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266875</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266875</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 21:05:13 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://cybercultural.com/p/lastfm-audioscrobbler-2002/"&gt;cybercultural.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;The best ”algorithm” for discovering new music was digging through profiles on last.fm back when the social functions of the site were still active. Sure, it was a lot of manual work, but the results were amazing. It wasn&amp;#x27;t completely blind, I found that people I had high similarity with, it was more likely I&amp;#x27;ll like what they like, even across different genres. Sometimes people were nice and took the effort to recommend based on my profile. I got introduced to varied music, different genres and even a bit from different countries.&lt;p&gt;The worst was Pandora, which did recommendations based on breakdown of musical instruments and elements in the song. It did what it aimed to do pretty well, only it was a bad idea. It gave you  a lot of uninspiring music that sounded like a bland copy of something you actually liked.&lt;p&gt;Spotify&amp;#x27;s recommendations are not super awful, but definitely feel closer to Pandora&amp;#x27;s style. I wonder why is the result like that even though I&amp;#x27;m sure they train their model based on listening history.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 192 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; cdrnsf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266875"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>192</hn_points><hn_author>cdrnsf</hn_author><hn_order>37</hn_order></item><item><title>Adafruit: Arduino’s Rules Are ‘Incompatible With Open Source’</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46265362</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46265362</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 18:18:34 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://thenewstack.io/adafruit-arduinos-rules-are-incompatible-with-open-source/"&gt;thenewstack.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Ever since I got involved with Espressif&amp;#x27;s ESP32&amp;#x2F;ESP8266 chips, I haven&amp;#x27;t even thought about arduinos, except to download the UI, but you don&amp;#x27;t even need to do that with the right VSCode extensions to make your life better.&lt;p&gt;I do keep meaning to try this though - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;platformio.org&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;platformio.org&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 191 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; MilnerRoute&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46265362"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>191</hn_points><hn_author>MilnerRoute</hn_author></item><item><title>Microsoft Copilot AI Comes to LG TVs, and Can't Be Deleted</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268844</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268844</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:35:41 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.techpowerup.com/344075/microsoft-copilot-ai-comes-to-lg-tvs-and-cant-be-deleted"&gt;www.techpowerup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;My rule for modern TVs:&lt;p&gt;1. Never connect the TV panel itself to the internet. Keep it air-gapped. Treat it solely as a dumb monitor.&lt;p&gt;2. Use an Apple TV for the &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot; features.&lt;p&gt;3. Avoid Fire TV, Chromecast, or Roku.&lt;p&gt;The logic is simple, Google (Chromecast) and Amazon (Fire TV) operate on the same business model as the TV manufacturers subsidized hardware in exchange for user data and ad inventory. Apple is the only mainstream option where the hardware cost covers the experience, rather than your viewing habits subsidizing the device.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 187 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; akyuu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268844"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>187</hn_points><hn_author>akyuu</hn_author><hn_order>25</hn_order></item><item><title>JSDoc is TypeScript</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266102</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266102</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:42:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://culi.bearblog.dev/jsdoc-is-typescript/"&gt;culi.bearblog.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;A few things I&amp;#x27;ve come to personally believe after spending years developing web and robotics software in Python&amp;#x2F;JavaScript then spending years having to maintain while constantly adding new features and dealing with company pivots:&lt;p&gt;- The types exist whether you write them down or not.&lt;p&gt;- If they&amp;#x27;re not written down, they&amp;#x27;re written down in your head.&lt;p&gt;- Your head is very volatile and hard for others to access.&lt;p&gt;- Typing is an incredibly good form of documentation.&lt;p&gt;- JSDoc and TypeScript are standards&amp;#x2F;formats for typing. Like any tools, they both have advantages and disadvantages. Neither is objectively better than the other.&lt;p&gt;- Make informed decisions on how you&amp;#x27;ll describe your types, and then be consistent and unsurprising.&lt;p&gt;- A type checker is the computer saying, &amp;quot;okay then, prove it&amp;quot; about your program&amp;#x27;s type validity.&lt;p&gt;- Not every program benefits from the same amount of &amp;quot;prove it.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;- Too much can be as bad as too little. You&amp;#x27;re wasting resources proving throwaway code.&lt;p&gt;- I like languages that let you decide how much you need to &amp;quot;prove it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 167 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; culi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266102"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>167</hn_points><hn_author>culi</hn_author><hn_order>17</hn_order></item><item><title>Roomba maker goes bankrupt, Chinese owner emerges</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268854</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268854</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:36:44 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/bankruptcy-law/robot-vacuum-roomba-maker-files-for-bankruptcy-after-35-years"&gt;news.bloomberglaw.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;7DyNA" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.ph&amp;#x2F;7DyNA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 160 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; nreece&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268854"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>160</hn_points><hn_author>nreece</hn_author><hn_order>4</hn_order></item><item><title>Rio de Janeiro's talipot palm trees bloom for the first and only time</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178966</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178966</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:42:37 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/brazil-rio-talipot-palm-flamengo-park-dcfb1ce237af7a10ab72205fc9bbdc02"&gt;apnews.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;The URL originally submitted is longer and more detailed than the AP article, but some HN readers question the quality of the writing and the origin of the photos. We&amp;#x27;ve made the AP article the main URL, but I&amp;#x27;m posting this comment with the original URL so readers can read it if interested to learn more.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.jardineriaon.com&amp;#x2F;The-talipot-palm-trees-of-Rio-de-Janeiro-bloom-for-the-first-and-only-time.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;en.jardineriaon.com&amp;#x2F;The-talipot-palm-trees-of-Rio-de...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 151 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; 1659447091&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178966"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>151</hn_points><hn_author>1659447091</hn_author><hn_order>18</hn_order></item><item><title>In the Beginning was the Command Line (1999)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46189905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46189905</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 08:44:06 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://web.stanford.edu/class/cs81n/command.txt"&gt;web.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Is this the origin of the classic analogy that Windows is a station wagon, Mac OS is a European luxury sedan, and Linux is a free tank? I had no idea that the author Neal Stephenson came up with that.&lt;p&gt;The analogy is definitely a bit outdated now, what with Windows 8 then 10 then 11 getting aggressively less user-friendly each year.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 151 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; wseqyrku&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46189905"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>151</hn_points><hn_author>wseqyrku</hn_author><hn_order>22</hn_order></item><item><title>iOS 26.2 fixes 20 security vulnerabilities, 2 actively exploited</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264101</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264101</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:13:55 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2025/12/12/ios-26-2-security-vulnerabilities/"&gt;www.macrumors.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Pro tip for anyone wanting to avoid liquid [gl]ass and install iOS 18.7.3: Apple is actively hiding 18.7.3 on most iPhones, despite the update showing on iPads. Perhaps a mistake, perhaps an attempt to force 26 onto users.&lt;p&gt;Simply select &amp;quot;iOS 18 Developer Beta&amp;quot; under beta updates (might need a developer account) and it will allow you to install it. The update currently offered is the production release.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 149 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; akyuu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264101"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>149</hn_points><hn_author>akyuu</hn_author><hn_order>53</hn_order></item><item><title>Price of a bot army revealed across online platforms</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264068</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264068</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:09:44 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cam.ac.uk/stories/price-bot-army-global-index"&gt;www.cam.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; They argue that SIM card regulation could help “disincentivise” online manipulation, and say their tool can be used to test policy interventions the world over.&lt;p&gt;In Germany, you have to give ISP customer providers (help centers) a copy of your passport ID in a live video stream to authenticate. That was introduced since 2013, for all SIM registrations.&lt;p&gt;So explain to me, again, how did this help reduce botnet traffic from Russia that uses proxy services of third parties that installed their proxy backdoors in free apps on the PlayStore under the disguise of marketing and advertisement?&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t understand why Google does not get any critique for allowing so much malware to be officially deployed via their PlayStore? They don&amp;#x27;t give a damn, have a history of not caring, and are the only point in the supply chain that is the problem. Every service provider that offers residential proxies is using those backdoors, and bought access for it from the advertisement companies.&lt;p&gt;If you report their Malware or Spamware, they ignore it. Try it, you will be disappointed. Because AdMob and other agencies are their customers. It&amp;#x27;s the same problem with Microsoft hosting Azure tenants that do spamming, sorry, &amp;quot;marketing campaigns&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;Source: I track these companies and their rotating ASNs with zero tolerance for spam. [1]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;cookiengineer&amp;#x2F;antispam" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;cookiengineer&amp;#x2F;antispam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 142 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; teleforce&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264068"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>142</hn_points><hn_author>teleforce</hn_author><hn_order>26</hn_order></item><item><title>GNU recutils: Plain text database</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46265811</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46265811</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:08:57 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/recutils/"&gt;www.gnu.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=22153665"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=22153665&lt;/a&gt; 505 points, 143 comments, 6 years ago&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=31832564"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=31832564&lt;/a&gt; 155 points, 52 comments, 3 years ago&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=15302035"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=15302035&lt;/a&gt; 105 points, 46 comments, 8 years ago&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 141 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; polyrand&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46265811"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>141</hn_points><hn_author>polyrand</hn_author><hn_order>51</hn_order></item><item><title>Getting into public speaking</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46216008</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46216008</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:03:56 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://james.brooks.page/blog/getting-into-public-speaking"&gt;james.brooks.page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m always surprised by the amount of advises in rehearsal.&lt;p&gt;I like to give public speaches, but I organize myself completely differently. I spend much time making Slides that are easy to follow and logically ordered, and in each I know that I can say a little more or a little less without disrupting the message. I know that I can count on 1 slide = 1 min. Unless lots of images.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t rehearse as I know that I prepared well my slides. Then during the talk I add more or less informations naturally depending on the time left and on the facial expressions of the audience. I usually finish exactly on time.&lt;p&gt;Usually I read my slides and think about what exactly to say only just before the talk.&lt;p&gt;I find this way more natural, and less scripted, and I usually get compliments on my presentation and naturalness. I think rehearsing removes much of the naturalness of a talk, unless that aspect is worked extensively, but that could sound a little too scripted for my taste.&lt;p&gt;One trick that I use often if I tend to forget some information that is important to say, is to put one word that trigger the information IN the slide, but in very light Grey, and in a natural place, like close to an image. So if I ever forget what to say, I have my landmarks in each slide to guide me.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 139 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; jbrooksuk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46216008"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>139</hn_points><hn_author>jbrooksuk</hn_author><hn_order>29</hn_order></item></channel></rss>