<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:11:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GrapheneOS is the only Android OS providing full security patches</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173407</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173407</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:58:31 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tbot.substack.com&amp;#x2F;p&amp;#x2F;grapheneos-new-oem-partnership" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tbot.substack.com&amp;#x2F;p&amp;#x2F;grapheneos-new-oem-partnership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;gt; GrapheneOS has officially confirmed a major new hardware partnership—one that marks the end of its long-standing Pixel exclusivity. According to the team, work with a major Android OEM began in June and is now moving toward the development of a next-generation smartphone built to meet GrapheneOS’ strict privacy and security standards.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://grapheneos.social/@GrapheneOS/115647408229616018"&gt;grapheneos.social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173407"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>449</hn_points><hn_author>akyuu</hn_author><hn_order>3</hn_order></item><item><title>Tiny Core Linux: a 23 MB Linux distro with graphical desktop</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173547</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173547</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:18:42 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;Tiny Core Linux has a version for Raspberry Pis called piCore [0] that I wish more people would look at, because it loads itself entirely into RAM and does not touch the SD card &lt;i&gt;at all&lt;/i&gt; after that until and unless you explicitly tell it to.&lt;p&gt;Phenomenal for those low powered servers you just want to leave on and running some tiny batch of cronjobs [1] or something for months or years at a time without worrying too much about wear on the SD card itself rendering the whole installation moot.&lt;p&gt;This is actually how I have powered the backend data collection and processing for [2], as I wrote about in [3]. The end result is a static site built in Hugo but I was careful to pick parts I could safely leave to wheedle on their own for a long time.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;consider-the-cronslave&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;consider-the-cronslave&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hiandrewquinn.github.io&amp;#x2F;selkouutiset-archive&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hiandrewquinn.github.io&amp;#x2F;selkouutiset-archive&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;lessons-learned-from-2-years-of-operating-a-tiny-news-archive&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;lessons-learned-from-2-yea...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.tinycorelinux.net/"&gt;www.tinycorelinux.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173547"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>347</hn_points><hn_author>LorenDB</hn_author><hn_order>5</hn_order></item><item><title>Z-Image: Powerful and highly efficient image generation model with 6B parameters</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46095817</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46095817</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:36:34 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve done some preliminary testing with Z-Image Turbo in the past week.&lt;p&gt;Thoughts&lt;p&gt;- It&amp;#x27;s fast (~3 seconds on my RTX 4090)&lt;p&gt;- Surprisingly capable of maintaining image integrity even at high resolutions (1536x1024, sometimes 2048x2048)&lt;p&gt;- The adherence is impressive for a 6B parameter model&lt;p&gt;Some tests (2 &amp;#x2F; 4 passed):&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;imgpb.com&amp;#x2F;exMoQ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;imgpb.com&amp;#x2F;exMoQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally I find it works better as a refiner model downstream of Qwen-Image 20b which has significantly better prompt understanding but has an unnatural &amp;quot;smoothness&amp;quot; to its generated images.&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Tongyi-MAI/Z-Image"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46095817"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>233</hn_points><hn_author>doener</hn_author><hn_order>9</hn_order></item><item><title>Autism's confusing cousins</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172443</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172443</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 11:18:40 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;I think part of the tension here comes from the way autism is understood both as a broad, fully-continuous, multivariate spectrum, and as a binary diagnosis.&lt;p&gt;To be sure, clinically, thresholds are useful because services, insurance, and research all rely on clear binary classifications, in our current society. But outside that context, it isn’t obvious that everyday language needs to mirror that line. Self-identification can be a way of making sense of one’s life, not an attempt to claim a clinical label.&lt;p&gt;But at the same time, the spectrum includes people with very high support needs, and there’s understandable concern that broad or casual uses of the term can hide those realities in ways that impact care.&lt;p&gt;To me, none of this means people are wrong for wondering about autism. And I do not have the experience to advocate for or against &amp;quot;anxiety disorders&amp;quot; being weighted more heavily in clinicians&amp;#x27; priors than they currently are (as the OP article heavily implies with its length). I mean only to highlight the mismatch between a binary diagnostic system and a very heterogeneous spectrum, and the need for language that acknowledges self-understanding without flattening anyone’s experience.&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.psychiatrymargins.com/p/autisms-confusing-cousins"&gt;www.psychiatrymargins.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172443"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>219</hn_points><hn_author>Anon84</hn_author><hn_order>15</hn_order></item><item><title>HTML as an Accessible Format for Papers</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173825</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173825</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:59:52 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;If the Unicode consortium would spend less time and effort on emoji and more on making the most common&amp;#x2F;important mathematical symbols and notations available&amp;#x2F;renderable in plain text, maybe we could move past the (LA)TeX&amp;#x2F;PDF marriage. OpenType and TrueType now (edit: for well over a decade, actually) support the necessary conditional rendering required to perform complicated rendering operations to get sequences of Unicode code points to display in the way needed (theoretically, anyway) and with fallback missing-glyph-only font family substitution support available pretty much everywhere allowing you to seamlessly display symbols not in your primary font from a fallback asset (something like Noto, with every Unicode symbol supported by design, or math-specific fonts like Cambria Math or TeX Gyre, etc), there are no technical restrictions.&lt;p&gt;I’ve actually dug into this in the past and it was never lack of technical ability that prevented them from even adding just proper superscript&amp;#x2F;subscript support before, but rather their opinion that this didn’t belong in the symbolic layer. But since emoji abuse&amp;#x2F;rely on ZWJ and modifiers left and right to display in one of a myriad of variations, there’s really no good reason not to allow the same, because 2 and the squares symbol are not semantically the same (so it’s not a design choice).&lt;p&gt;An interesting (complete) tangent is that Gemini 3 Pro is the only model I’ve tested (I do a lot of math-related stuff with LLMs) that absolutely will not under any circumstances respect (system&amp;#x2F;user) prompt requests to avoid inline math mode (aka LATeX) in the output, regardless of whether I asked for a blanket ban on TeX&amp;#x2F;MathJax&amp;#x2F;etc or when I insisted that it use extended unicode codes points to substitute all math formula rendering (I primarily use LLMs via the TUI where I don’t have MathJax support, and as familiar as I once was with raw TeX mathematical notations and symbols, it’s still quite easy to confuse unrendered raw output by missing something if you’re not careful). I shared my experiment and results here – Gemini 3 Pro would insist on even rendering single letter constants or variables as $k$ instead of just k (or k in markdown italics, etc) no matter how hard I asked it not to (which makes me think it may have been overfit against raw LATeX papers, and is also an interesting argument in favor of the “VL LLMs are the more natural construct”):
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;NeoSmart&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1995582721327071367?s=20" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;NeoSmart&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1995582721327071367?s=20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://info.arxiv.org/about/accessible_HTML.html"&gt;info.arxiv.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173825"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>198</hn_points><hn_author>el3ctron</hn_author><hn_order>11</hn_order></item><item><title>The unexpected effectiveness of one-shot decompilation with Claude</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080498</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080498</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:07:48 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;For anyone else who was initially confused by this, useful context is that Snowboard Kids 2 is an N64 game.&lt;p&gt;I also wasn&amp;#x27;t familiar with this terminology:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; You hand it a function; it tries to match it, and you move on.&lt;p&gt;In decompilation &amp;quot;matching&amp;quot; means you found a function block in the machine code, wrote some C, then confirmed that the C produces the exact same binary machine code once it is compiled.&lt;p&gt;The author&amp;#x27;s previous post explains this all in a bunch more detail: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.chrislewis.au&amp;#x2F;using-coding-agents-to-decompile-nintendo-64-games&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.chrislewis.au&amp;#x2F;using-coding-agents-to-decompile-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blog.chrislewis.au/the-unexpected-effectiveness-of-one-shot-decompilation-with-claude/"&gt;blog.chrislewis.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080498"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>174</hn_points><hn_author>knackers</hn_author><hn_order>26</hn_order></item><item><title>Touching the Elephant – TPUs</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172797</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172797</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 12:29:28 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;The Scaling ML textbook also has an excellent section on TPUs.
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jax-ml.github.io&amp;#x2F;scaling-book&amp;#x2F;tpus&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jax-ml.github.io&amp;#x2F;scaling-book&amp;#x2F;tpus&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://considerthebulldog.com/tte-tpu/"&gt;considerthebulldog.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172797"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>152</hn_points><hn_author>giuliomagnifico</hn_author><hn_order>23</hn_order></item><item><title>Linux Instal Fest Belgrade</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172167</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172167</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 10:20:19 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;I remember organizing Linux install parties at my university (University of Lille (1), in France), each year for like 3 to 4 consecutive years.&lt;p&gt;It was always a pleasure to meet new people and explain how basically &amp;quot;their computer is working&amp;quot; and how they can free from Windows.&lt;p&gt;The most interested person at that time was a 55 years old woman who knew nothing in computer. I installed Ubuntu on its computer and she came the next year with strong system knowledge for a linux-newbie, and the same laptop... with Debian in it!&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://dmz.rs/lif2025_en"&gt;dmz.rs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172167"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>150</hn_points><hn_author>ubavic</hn_author><hn_order>29</hn_order></item><item><title>OMSCS Open Courseware</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175826</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175826</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:14:35 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;Current OMSCS grad student; three down, seven to go. Loving the program so far.&lt;p&gt;The content is great, and most of it is available on Open Courseware, YT, etc, but here&amp;#x27;s what else you get by officially going through the program:&lt;p&gt;- the amazing community of TAs&lt;p&gt;- the assignments&lt;p&gt;- the feedback on reports &amp;amp; projects (either automated, or through TAs)&lt;p&gt;- the collaboration with other students on Ed, Discord, Slack, etc&lt;p&gt;- the forcing function of deadlines, having to study for exams, etc&lt;p&gt;- free access to academic libraries, IEEE, ACM, O&amp;#x27;Reilly, etc&lt;p&gt;- access to software and services, educational packages from GitHub, Wolfram, Google Colab Pro, student discount in a bunch of places, etc&lt;p&gt;Another underrated aspect is GT&amp;#x27;s ability to preserve rigor of the program overall, despite the scale and number of students in some courses (the most popular ones have 1,000-1,500 students per semester).&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#x27;re on the fence on applying, I strongly recommend you do. The program is affordable enough that there&amp;#x27;s no harm in trying for a few semesters to see if matches what you&amp;#x27;re looking for.&lt;p&gt;Glad to answer any questions.&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://sites.gatech.edu/omscsopencourseware/"&gt;sites.gatech.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175826"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>121</hn_points><hn_author>kerim-ca</hn_author><hn_order>8</hn_order></item><item><title>Screenshots from developers: 2002 vs. 2015 (2015)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46176905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46176905</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 21:55:09 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;quote&gt;Interesting how Brian works. I guess it is the UNIX spirit
he carries there. Or perhaps he is damn fast with the tabbed
WM. Or is that OSX?&lt;p&gt;I use mostly IceWM these days. I can&amp;#x27;t use the leaner WMs such
as ion or ratpoison and XFCE, mate-desktop, KDE and GNOME are
too slow or too crap (KDE unfortunately also now; before that
only GNOME was crap. KDE killing xorg-support also means it
is one less thing I can use anyway.)&lt;/quote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://anders.unix.se/2015/12/10/screenshots-from-developers--2002-vs.-2015/"&gt;anders.unix.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46176905"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>116</hn_points><hn_author>turrini</hn_author></item></channel></rss>