<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Auto-grading decade-old Hacker News discussions with hindsight</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:23:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://karpathy.bearblog.dev/auto-grade-hn/"&gt;karpathy.bearblog.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Related from yesterday: &lt;i&gt;Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 imagines the HN front page 10 years from now&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s fun to read some of these historic comments! A while back I wrote a replay system to better capture how discussions evolved at the time of these historic threads. Here&amp;#x27;s Karpathy&amp;#x27;s list from his graded articles, in the replay visualizer:&lt;p&gt;Swift is Open Source
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10669891" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10669891&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launch of Figma, a collaborative interface design tool
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10685407" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10685407&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing OpenAI
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10720176" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10720176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first person to hack the iPhone is building a self-driving car
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10744206" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10744206&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;SpaceX launch webcast: Orbcomm-2 Mission [video]
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10774865" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10774865&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Theranos, Many Strategies and Snags
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10799261" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10799261&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 664 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; __rito__&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>664</hn_points><hn_author>__rito__</hn_author><hn_order>41</hn_order></item><item><title>Sick of smart TVs? Here are your best options</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46243655</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46243655</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:51:40 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/12/the-ars-technica-guide-to-dumb-tvs/"&gt;arstechnica.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;For a hacker news article, it misses the crucial option - hacking a smart TV! I have LG OLED jailbroken using rootmy.tv, it was pretty trivial. It&amp;#x27;s basically a linux computer with a huge screen, you can customize it, SSH into it, map any commands to the remote, etc.&lt;p&gt;Before I only used monitor, simple DP&amp;#x2F;HDMI input is all I wanted. But being able to take full control of the tv and connect it with other devices in the house I would normally get Rpi for is pretty convenient!&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 582 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; fleahunter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46243655"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>582</hn_points><hn_author>fleahunter</hn_author><hn_order>44</hn_order></item><item><title>OpenAI are quietly adopting skills, now available in ChatGPT and Codex CLI</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250332</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250332</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 23:30:19 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Dec/12/openai-skills/"&gt;simonwillison.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;LLMs need prompts. Prompts can get very big very quickly. The so called &amp;quot;skills&amp;quot;, which exist in other forms in other platforms outside of Anthropic and OpenAI, are simply a mechanism to extend the prompt dynamically. The tool (scripts) that are part of the skill are no different then simply having the tools already installed in the OS where the agent operates.&lt;p&gt;The idea behind skills is sound because context management matters.&lt;p&gt;However, skills are different from MCP. Skills has nothing to do with tool calling at all!&lt;p&gt;You can implement your own version of skills easily and there is absolutely zero need for any kind of standard or a framework of sorts. They way to do is to register a tool &amp;#x2F; function to load and extend the base prompt and presto - you have implemented your own version of skills.&lt;p&gt;In ChatBotKit AI Widget we even have our own version of that for both the server and when building client-side applications.&lt;p&gt;With client-side applications the whole thing is implemented with a simple react hook that adds the necessary tools to extend the prompt dynamically. You can easily come up with your own implementation of that with 20-30 lines of code. It is not complicated.&lt;p&gt;Very often people latch on some idea thinking this is the next big thing hoping that it will explode. It is not new and it wont explode! It is just part of a suite of tools that already exist in various forms. The mechanic is so simple at its core that practically makes no sense to call it a standard and there is absolutely zero need to have it for most types of applications. It does make sense for coding assistant though as they work with quite a bit of data so there it matters. But skills are not fundamentally different from *.instruction.md prompt in Copilot or AGENT.md and its variations.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 552 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; simonw&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250332"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>552</hn_points><hn_author>simonw</hn_author><hn_order>37</hn_order></item><item><title>macOS 26.2 enables fast AI clusters with RDMA over Thunderbolt</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46248644</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46248644</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:41:38 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/macos-release-notes/macos-26_2-release-notes#RDMA-over-Thunderbolt"&gt;developer.apple.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I follow the MLX team on Twitter and they sometimes post about using MLX on two or more joined together Macs to run models that need more than 512GB of RAM.&lt;p&gt;A couple of examples:&lt;p&gt;Kimi K2 Thinking (1 trillion parameters): &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;awnihannun&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1986601104130646266" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;awnihannun&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1986601104130646266&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;DeepSeek R1 (671B): &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;awnihannun&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1881915166922863045" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;awnihannun&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1881915166922863045&lt;/a&gt; - that one came with setup instructions in a Gist: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;gist.github.com&amp;#x2F;awni&amp;#x2F;ec071fd27940698edd14a4191855bba6" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;gist.github.com&amp;#x2F;awni&amp;#x2F;ec071fd27940698edd14a4191855bba...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 521 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; guiand&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46248644"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>521</hn_points><hn_author>guiand</hn_author><hn_order>54</hn_order></item><item><title>What is the nicest thing a stranger has ever done for you?</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236001</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236001</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 19:28:40 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://louplummer.lol/nice-stranger/"&gt;louplummer.lol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;A friend of mine and I (we are both Aussies) had been staying at my Grandma&amp;#x27;s house in a rural village in UK and were trying to make our way back to London on Boxing Day. The fact that it was Boxing Day meant that no buses were running, so we started sticking our thumbs out to try and hitch a lift to the nearest town&amp;#x27;s train station. As you would expect, picking up two 19 year old blokes in the middle of nowhere was not an attractive proposition to your average passerby.&lt;p&gt;Eventually a guy comes along and picks us up. Tells us he hitched all the way across Europe back in the day so he empathized with us. Says he&amp;#x27;s on the way to pick up his son (our age) from work, a department store that happened to be on the way to the station.&lt;p&gt;His son gets into the car, understandably pretty bemused as to why his dad has brought two random stragglers with him!&lt;p&gt;We get to the station only to find that it&amp;#x27;s closed, because, yes, it&amp;#x27;s Boxing Day and trains weren&amp;#x27;t running either (we hadn&amp;#x27;t really thought this through). Guy says:&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Don&amp;#x27;t worry lads, all the family are around ours for Christmas dinner. My brother lives in West London so he can give you a ride there at the end of the night.&amp;quot;&lt;p&gt;So we found ourselves, two foreign students, invited to a complete stranger&amp;#x27;s Christmas dinner party. We all had so much fun and drank so much that we completely abandoned the London idea and went back to my Grandma&amp;#x27;s at the end of the night.&lt;p&gt;And the kid who was our age that got picked up from work? He ended up being my Best Man when I got married 15 years later. True story!&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 378 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; speckx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236001"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>378</hn_points><hn_author>speckx</hn_author><hn_order>31</hn_order></item><item><title>VPN location claims don't match real traffic exits</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257339</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257339</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:46:19 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://ipinfo.io/blog/vpn-location-mismatch-report"&gt;ipinfo.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m a co-founder at WonderProxy, we didn&amp;#x27;t make their list (we target people doing application testing, not consumer VPNs).&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;re in 100+ countries, and I&amp;#x27;ll stand by that claim. It&amp;#x27;s a huge pain in the neck. In our early years we had a lot of problems with suppliers claiming to be in Mexico or South America who were actually just in Texas. I almost flew to Peru with a rackmount server in my luggage after weeks of problems, that plan died when we realized I&amp;#x27;d need to figure out how to pay Peruvian income tax on the money I made in country before I could leave.&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#x27;ve also had customers complaining that a given competitor had a country we&amp;#x27;d had trouble sourcing in the Middle East. A little digging on our part and it&amp;#x27;s less than a ms away from our server in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 369 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; mmaia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257339"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>369</hn_points><hn_author>mmaia</hn_author><hn_order>13</hn_order></item><item><title>Ask HN: How can I get better at using AI for programming?</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255285</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255285</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:37:16 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255285"&gt;news.ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been working on a personal project recently, rewriting an old jQuery + Django project into SvelteKit. The main work is translating the UI templates into idiomatic SvelteKit while maintaining the original styling. This includes things like using semantic HTML instead of div-spamming, not wrapping divs in divs in divs, and replacing bootstrap with minimal tailwind. It also includes some logic refactors, to maintain the original functionality but rewritten to avoid years of code debt. Things like replacing templates using boolean flags for multiple views with composable Svelte components.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve had a fairly steady process for doing this: look at each route defined in Django, build out my `+page.server.ts`, and then split each major section of the page into a Svelte component with a matching Storybook story. It takes a lot of time to do this, since I have to ensure I&amp;#x27;m not just copying the template but rather recreating it in a more idiomatic style.&lt;p&gt;This kind of work seems like a great use case for AI assisted programming, but I&amp;#x27;ve failed to use it effectively. At most, I can only get Claude Code to recreate some slightly less spaghetti code in Svelte. Simple prompting just isn&amp;#x27;t able to get AI&amp;#x27;s code quality within 90% of what I&amp;#x27;d write by hand. Ideally, AI could get it&amp;#x27;s code to something I could review manually in 15-20 minutes, which would massively speed up the time spent on this project (right now it takes me 1-2 hours to properly translate a route).&lt;p&gt;Do you guys have tips or suggestions on how to improve my efficiency and code quality with AI?&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Hey, Boris from the Claude Code team here. A few tips:&lt;p&gt;1. If there is anything Claude tends to repeatedly get wrong, not understand, or spend lots of tokens on, put it in your CLAUDE.md. Claude automatically reads this file and it’s a great way to avoid repeating yourself. I add to my team’s CLAUDE.md multiple times a week.&lt;p&gt;2. Use Plan mode (press shift-tab 2x). Go back and forth with Claude until you like the plan before you let Claude execute. This easily 2-3x’s results for harder tasks.&lt;p&gt;3. Give the model a way to check its work. For svelte, consider using the Puppeteer MCP server and tell Claude to check its work in the browser. This is another 2-3x.&lt;p&gt;4. Use Opus 4.5. It’s a step change from Sonnet 4.5 and earlier models.&lt;p&gt;Hope that helps!&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 334 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; lemonlime227&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255285"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>334</hn_points><hn_author>lemonlime227</hn_author><hn_order>23</hn_order></item><item><title>Useful patterns for building HTML tools</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223882</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223882</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:08:41 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Dec/10/html-tools/"&gt;simonwillison.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Thanks Simon!&lt;p&gt;My tool collection [0] is inspired by yours, with a handful of differences. I&amp;#x27;m only at 53 tools at the moment.&lt;p&gt;What I did differently:&lt;p&gt;Hosted on Cloudflare Pages. This gives you preview URLs for pull requests out the box. This might be possible with Github Pages but I haven&amp;#x27;t checked. I&amp;#x27;ve used Vercel for similar projects in the past. Cloudflare seems to have the odd failed build that needs a kick from their dashboard.&lt;p&gt;Some tools can make use of Workers&amp;#x2F;Functions for backend processing and secrets. I try to keep these to a minimum but they&amp;#x27;re occasionally useful.&lt;p&gt;I have an AGENTS.md that&amp;#x27;s updated with a Github action to automatically pull in Claude-style Skills from the .skills directory. I blogged about this pattern and am still waiting for a standard to evolve [2].&lt;p&gt;I have a base stylesheet that I instruct agents to pull in. This gives a bit of consistency and also let&amp;#x27;s them use Tailwind, which they&amp;#x27;d seem to love.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tools.dave.engineer&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tools.dave.engineer&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dave1010&amp;#x2F;tools&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;functions" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;dave1010&amp;#x2F;tools&amp;#x2F;tree&amp;#x2F;main&amp;#x2F;functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dave.engineer&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;skills-to-agents&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dave.engineer&amp;#x2F;blog&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;skills-to-agents&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 286 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; simonw&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223882"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>286</hn_points><hn_author>simonw</hn_author><hn_order>15</hn_order></item><item><title>I tried Gleam for Advent of Code</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255991</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255991</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:00:14 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/gleamaoc2025/"&gt;blog.tymscar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Gleam is a beautiful language, and what I wish Elixir would become (re:typing).&lt;p&gt;For those that don&amp;#x27;t know its also built upon OTP, the erlang vm that makes concurrency and queues a trivial problem in my opinion.&lt;p&gt;Absolutely wonderful ecosystem.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve been wanting to make Gleam my primary language, but I fear LLMs have frozen programming language advancement and adoption for anything past 2021.&lt;p&gt;But I am hopeful that Gleam has slid just under the closing door and LLMs will get up to speed on it fast.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 285 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; tymscar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255991"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>285</hn_points><hn_author>tymscar</hn_author><hn_order>5</hn_order></item><item><title>Computer animator and Amiga fanatic Dick van Dyke turns 100</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252993</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252993</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 08:15:48 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252993"&gt;news.ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#x27;s a video from 2004 &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=Y1J9kfDCAmU" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.youtube.com&amp;#x2F;watch?v=Y1J9kfDCAmU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s his 100th birthday today.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Here’s a great quote by him:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; In my 30’s, I exercised to look good. In my 50’s, to stay fit. In my 70’s, to stay ambulatory. In my 80’s, to avoid assisted living. Now in my 90’s, I’m just doing it out of pure defiance&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 245 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; ggm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252993"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>245</hn_points><hn_author>ggm</hn_author><hn_order>46</hn_order></item><item><title>Why Twilio Segment moved from microservices back to a monolith</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257714</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257714</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 20:30:34 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.twilio.com/en-us/blog/developers/best-practices/goodbye-microservices"&gt;www.twilio.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Once the code for all destinations lived in a single repo, they could be merged into a single service. With every destination living in one service, our developer productivity substantially improved. We no longer had to deploy 140+ services for a change to one of the shared libraries. One engineer can deploy the service in a matter of minutes.&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;i&gt;must&lt;/i&gt; to deploy every service because of a library change, you don&amp;#x27;t have services, you have a distributed monolith. The entire idea of a &amp;quot;shared library&amp;quot; which must be kept updated across your entire service fleet is antithetical to how you need to treat services.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 230 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; birdculture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257714"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>230</hn_points><hn_author>birdculture</hn_author><hn_order>20</hn_order></item><item><title>Linux Sandboxes and Fil-C</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259064</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259064</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 22:58:29 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://fil-c.org/seccomp"&gt;fil-c.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a hybrid approach of C -&amp;gt; WASM -&amp;gt; C compilation, which ends up controlling every OS interaction and sandboxing memory access like WASM, while technically remaining C code:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rlbox.dev&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;rlbox.dev&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 228 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; pizlonator&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259064"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>228</hn_points><hn_author>pizlonator</hn_author><hn_order>1</hn_order></item><item><title>Recovering Anthony Bourdain's Li.st's</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258163</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258163</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 21:18:01 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://sandyuraz.com/blogs/bourdain/"&gt;sandyuraz.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I have never been particularly fond of Bourdain, nor have I fully understood the widespread fascination with his jet-setting New York hipster persona.&lt;p&gt;He played a significant role in popularizing a now-familiar posture among affluent Americans: the earnest declaration that &amp;quot;travel is my passion&amp;quot;, followed by carefully curated excursions to economically disadvantaged countries, enthusiastic consumption of the local cuisine, and a subsequent return home marked by self-congratulatory reflections on how much they have supposedly &amp;quot;learned&amp;quot; about other cultures.&lt;p&gt;The phenomenon is difficult to admire. It resembles a kind of cultural primitivism - an unintentional revival of archaic rituals in which consuming the body of the enemy was believed to confer insight, power, or spiritual essence. In this modern iteration, wealth functions as the enabling mechanism: privileged travelers fly abroad to ingest cuisines, aesthetics, and experiences, mistaking consumption for understanding and appetite for empathy.&lt;p&gt;One returns, enriched - spiritually, one assumes - having &lt;i&gt;eaten&lt;/i&gt; well.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 206 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; thecsw&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258163"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>206</hn_points><hn_author>thecsw</hn_author><hn_order>4</hn_order></item><item><title>Go Proposal: Secret Mode</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46210705</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46210705</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 21:10:52 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://antonz.org/accepted/runtime-secret/"&gt;antonz.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;FTA: &lt;i&gt;“Heap allocations made by the function are erased as soon as the garbage collector decides they are no longer reachable”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that means this proposal adds a very specific form of finalisers to go.&lt;p&gt;How is that implemented efficiently? I can think of doing something akin to NSAutoReleasePool (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developer.apple.com&amp;#x2F;documentation&amp;#x2F;foundation&amp;#x2F;nsautoreleasepool" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;developer.apple.com&amp;#x2F;documentation&amp;#x2F;foundation&amp;#x2F;nsautor...&lt;/a&gt;), with all allocations inside a `secret.Do` block going into a separate section of the heap (like a new generation), and, on exit of the block, the runtime doing a GC cycle, collecting and clearing every now inaccessible object in that section of the heap.&lt;p&gt;It can’t do that, though, because the article also says:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Heap allocations are only erased if  the program drops all references to them, and  then the garbage collector notices that those references are gone. The program controls the first part, but the second part depends on when the runtime decides to act”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;and I think what I am thinking of will guarantee that the garbage collector will eagerly erase any heap allocations that can be freed.&lt;p&gt;Also, the requirement “ the program drops all references to them” means this is not a 100% free lunch. You can’t simply wrap your code in a `secret.Do` and expect your code to be free of leaking secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 193 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; enz&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46210705"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>193</hn_points><hn_author>enz</hn_author><hn_order>18</hn_order></item><item><title>I fed 24 years of my blog posts to a Markov model</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257607</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257607</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 20:19:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://susam.net/fed-24-years-of-posts-to-markov-model.html"&gt;susam.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;In the discussion thread there seems to be a somewhat contentious argument about what is a Markov Model, whether LLMs are one, RNNs are one and so on.&lt;p&gt;Markov Models are anything that has state and emit tokens based &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; on its current state and undergoes a state transition. The token emission and state transitions are usually probabilistic -- a statistical&amp;#x2F;probabilistic analogue of a state machine. The deterministic state machine is a special case where the transition probabilities are degenerate (concentrated at an unique point).&lt;p&gt;For a Markov Model to be non-vacuous, non-vapid discussion point, however, one needs to specify very precisely the relationships allowed between state and tokens&amp;#x2F;observations, whether it&amp;#x27;s hidden or visible, discrete or continuous, fixed context length or variable context length, causal or non causal ...&lt;p&gt;The simplest such model is one where the state is a specified, computable function of the last k observations. One such simple function is the identity function -- the state then is the last k tokens.  This is called a k order &lt;i&gt;Markov Chain&lt;/i&gt; and is a restriction of the bigger class -- &lt;i&gt;Markov Models&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;One can make the state a specified, computable function of &lt;i&gt;(k) previous states and&lt;/i&gt; k most recent tokens&amp;#x2F;observations. (Equivalently RNNs)&lt;p&gt;The functions may be specified only upto a class of computable functions, finite or infinite in size. They may be stochastic in the sense they define only the state transition probabilities.&lt;p&gt;You can make the context length a computable function of the k most recent observations (therefore they can be of varying length), but you have to ensure that the contexts are always full for this model to be well defined.&lt;p&gt;Context length can be a computable function of both the (&lt;i&gt;el&lt;/i&gt;) most recent states and k most recent observations.&lt;p&gt;Crazy ones emit more than one token based on current state.&lt;p&gt;On and on.&lt;p&gt;Not all Markov Models are learnable.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 184 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; zdw&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257607"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>184</hn_points><hn_author>zdw</hn_author><hn_order>3</hn_order></item><item><title>Ensuring a National Policy Framework for Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46239076</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46239076</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 23:56:10 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/12/eliminating-state-law-obstruction-of-national-artificial-intelligence-policy/"&gt;www.whitehouse.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cnbc.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;12&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;trump-signs-executive-order-for-single-national-ai-regulation-framework.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.cnbc.com&amp;#x2F;2025&amp;#x2F;12&amp;#x2F;11&amp;#x2F;trump-signs-executive-order-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nbcnews.com&amp;#x2F;tech&amp;#x2F;tech-news&amp;#x2F;trump-signs-executive-order-seeking-ban-state-laws-ai-rcna248741" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.nbcnews.com&amp;#x2F;tech&amp;#x2F;tech-news&amp;#x2F;trump-signs-executive...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Is it me or does this seem like naked corruption at its worst? These tech CEOs hang out at the White House and donate to superfluous causes and suddenly the executive is protecting their interests. This does nothing to protect working US citizens from AI alien (agents) coming to take their jobs and displace their incomes.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 178 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; andsoitis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46239076"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>178</hn_points><hn_author>andsoitis</hn_author><hn_order>53</hn_order></item><item><title>Photographer built a medium-format rangefinder</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46177160</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46177160</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 22:29:29 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://petapixel.com/2025/12/06/this-photographer-built-an-awesome-medium-format-rangefinder-and-so-can-you/"&gt;petapixel.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;The level of integration of little electronics (like the LiDAR and the OLED screen) into a print is amazing! I am thinking about an electronic light meter that is coupled to the shutter and saves the current reading to an SD card, so that you could later sync the EXIF data to the scans.&lt;p&gt;Shameless plug: I have made a website that lists a lot of 3D printable film cameras (including the links to the print files). Feel free to have a look if you are thinking about printing your own camera. Some are really cheap and easy to print.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;printed.analogcamera.space" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;printed.analogcamera.space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 171 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; shinryuu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46177160"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>171</hn_points><hn_author>shinryuu</hn_author><hn_order>34</hn_order></item><item><title>Go is portable, until it isn't</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46180911</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46180911</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:17:42 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://simpleobservability.com/blog/go-portable-until-isnt"&gt;simpleobservability.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I ran into this issue when porting term.everything[0] from typescript to go. I had some c library dependencies that I did need to link, so I had to use cgo. 
My solution was to do the build process on alpine linux[1] and use static linking[2]. This way it statically links musl libc, which is much friendlier with static linking than glibc.
Now, I have a static binary that runs in alpine, Debian, and even bare containers.&lt;p&gt;Since I have made the change, I have not had anyone open any issues saying they had problems running it on their machines. (Unlike when I was using AppImages, which caused  much more trouble than I expected)&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;mmulet&amp;#x2F;term.everything" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;mmulet&amp;#x2F;term.everything&lt;/a&gt; 
look at distribute.sh and the makefile to see how I did it.&lt;p&gt;[1]in a podman or docker container&lt;p&gt;[2] -ldflags &amp;#x27;-extldflags &amp;quot;-static&amp;quot;&amp;#x27;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 147 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; khazit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46180911"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>147</hn_points><hn_author>khazit</hn_author><hn_order>42</hn_order></item><item><title>Are we stuck with the same Desktop UX forever? [video]</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256834</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256834</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 18:39:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1fZTOjd_bOQ"&gt;www.youtube.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I understand the desire to want to fix user pain points. There are plenty to choose from. I think the problem is that most of the UI changes don&amp;#x27;t seem to fix any particular issue I have. They are just different, and when some changes do create even more problems there&amp;#x27;s never any configuration to disable them. You&amp;#x27;re trying to create a perfect, coherent system for everyone absent the ability to configure it to our liking. He even mentioned how unpopular making things configurable is in the UI community.&lt;p&gt;A perfect pain point example was mentioned in the video: Text selection on mobile is trash. But each app seems to have different solutions, even from the same developer. Google Messages doesn&amp;#x27;t allow any text selection of content below an entire message. Some other apps have opted in to a &amp;#x27;smart&amp;#x27; text select which when you select text will guess and randomly group select adjacent words. And lastly, some apps will only ever select a single word when you double tap which seemed to be the standard on mobile for a long time. All of this is inconsistent and often I&amp;#x27;ll want to do something like look up a word and realize oh I can&amp;#x27;t select the word at all (G message), or the system &amp;#x27;smartly&amp;#x27; selected 4 words instead, or that it did what I want and actually just picked one word. Each application designer decided they wanted to make their own change and made the whole system fragmented and worse overall.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 144 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; joelkesler&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256834"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>144</hn_points><hn_author>joelkesler</hn_author><hn_order>49</hn_order></item><item><title>Freeing a Xiaomi humidifier from the cloud</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46241368</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46241368</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:17:28 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://0l.de/blog/2025/11/xiaomi-humidifier/"&gt;0l.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;On a tangent note: don’t use ultrasonic humidifiers. Unless distilled water is used, they create a shit-ton of pm2.5 particles.&lt;p&gt;Use evaporative humidifiers (just disks with myriads of small notches for water to cling on and a fan): &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;us.smartmiglobal.com&amp;#x2F;pages&amp;#x2F;smartmi-evaporative-humidifier-3" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;us.smartmiglobal.com&amp;#x2F;pages&amp;#x2F;smartmi-evaporative-humid...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 142 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; stv0g&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46241368"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>142</hn_points><hn_author>stv0g</hn_author><hn_order>45</hn_order></item></channel></rss>