<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:30:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160315</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160315</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:21:19 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Any consolidation like this seems like a negative for consumers. But at least it wasn’t bought by Larry Ellison, as was considered very likely (assuming this merger gets approved, in the current administration you never know).&lt;p&gt;From a Hacker News perspective, I wonder what this means for engineers working on HBO Max. Netflix says they’re keeping the company separate but surely you’d be looking to move them to Netflix backend infrastructure at the very least.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://about.netflix.com/en/news/netflix-to-acquire-warner-bros"&gt;about.netflix.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160315"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>1680</hn_points><hn_author>meetpateltech</hn_author><hn_order>36</hn_order></item><item><title>Netflix’s AV1 Journey: From Android to TVs and Beyond</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155135</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155135</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:09:57 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow. To me, the big news here is that ~30% of devices now support AV1 hardware decoding. The article lists a bunch of examples of devices that have gained it in the past few years. I had no idea it was getting that popular -- fantastic news!&lt;p&gt;So now that h.264, h.265, and AV1 seem to be the three major codecs with hardware support, I wonder what will be the next one?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://netflixtechblog.com/av1-now-powering-30-of-netflix-streaming-02f592242d80"&gt;netflixtechblog.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155135"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>535</hn_points><hn_author>CharlesW</hn_author><hn_order>40</hn_order></item><item><title>GrapheneOS is the only Android OS providing full security patches</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173407</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173407</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:58:31 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tbot.substack.com&amp;#x2F;p&amp;#x2F;grapheneos-new-oem-partnership" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;tbot.substack.com&amp;#x2F;p&amp;#x2F;grapheneos-new-oem-partnership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;gt; GrapheneOS has officially confirmed a major new hardware partnership—one that marks the end of its long-standing Pixel exclusivity. According to the team, work with a major Android OEM began in June and is now moving toward the development of a next-generation smartphone built to meet GrapheneOS’ strict privacy and security standards.&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://grapheneos.social/@GrapheneOS/115647408229616018"&gt;grapheneos.social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173407"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>459</hn_points><hn_author>akyuu</hn_author><hn_order>3</hn_order></item><item><title>How I discovered a hidden microphone on a Chinese NanoKVM</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173383</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173383</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:54:59 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To be fair, the microphone _is_ listed on the specsheet of the LicheeRV Nano&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;wiki.sipeed.com&amp;#x2F;hardware&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;lichee&amp;#x2F;RV_Nano&amp;#x2F;1_intro.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;wiki.sipeed.com&amp;#x2F;hardware&amp;#x2F;en&amp;#x2F;lichee&amp;#x2F;RV_Nano&amp;#x2F;1_intro.h...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I assume they didn&amp;#x27;t intend to put a  mic on the KVM product, but they wanted to make a KVM product, already had this SBC product, which reusing their existing stock of helped keep cost low.&lt;p&gt;Should they have been more up front about it it? Sure, and it&amp;#x27;s not great that they had a bunch of security issues in the FW anyway, so not exactly great, but &amp;quot;hidden microphone in a Chinese KVM&amp;quot; lets the mind wander&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://telefoncek.si/2025/02/2025-02-10-hidden-microphone-on-nanokvm/"&gt;telefoncek.si&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173383"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>366</hn_points><hn_author>ementally</hn_author><hn_order>37</hn_order></item><item><title>Tiny Core Linux: a 23 MB Linux distro with graphical desktop</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173547</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173547</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:18:42 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tiny Core Linux has a version for Raspberry Pis called piCore [0] that I wish more people would look at, because it loads itself entirely into RAM and does not touch the SD card &lt;i&gt;at all&lt;/i&gt; after that until and unless you explicitly tell it to.&lt;p&gt;Phenomenal for those low powered servers you just want to leave on and running some tiny batch of cronjobs [1] or something for months or years at a time without worrying too much about wear on the SD card itself rendering the whole installation moot.&lt;p&gt;This is actually how I have powered the backend data collection and processing for [2], as I wrote about in [3]. The end result is a static site built in Hugo but I was careful to pick parts I could safely leave to wheedle on their own for a long time.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;consider-the-cronslave&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;consider-the-cronslave&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hiandrewquinn.github.io&amp;#x2F;selkouutiset-archive&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hiandrewquinn.github.io&amp;#x2F;selkouutiset-archive&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;lessons-learned-from-2-years-of-operating-a-tiny-news-archive&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;til.andrew-quinn.me&amp;#x2F;posts&amp;#x2F;lessons-learned-from-2-yea...&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.tinycorelinux.net/"&gt;www.tinycorelinux.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173547"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>352</hn_points><hn_author>LorenDB</hn_author><hn_order>6</hn_order></item><item><title>Z-Image: Powerful and highly efficient image generation model with 6B parameters</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46095817</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46095817</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:36:34 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#x27;ve done some preliminary testing with Z-Image Turbo in the past week.&lt;p&gt;Thoughts&lt;p&gt;- It&amp;#x27;s fast (~3 seconds on my RTX 4090)&lt;p&gt;- Surprisingly capable of maintaining image integrity even at high resolutions (1536x1024, sometimes 2048x2048)&lt;p&gt;- The adherence is impressive for a 6B parameter model&lt;p&gt;Some tests (2 &amp;#x2F; 4 passed):&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;imgpb.com&amp;#x2F;exMoQ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;imgpb.com&amp;#x2F;exMoQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally I find it works better as a refiner model downstream of Qwen-Image 20b which has significantly better prompt understanding but has an unnatural &amp;quot;smoothness&amp;quot; to its generated images.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Tongyi-MAI/Z-Image"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46095817"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>237</hn_points><hn_author>doener</hn_author><hn_order>11</hn_order></item><item><title>Autism's confusing cousins</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172443</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172443</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 11:18:40 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think part of the tension here comes from the way autism is understood both as a broad, fully-continuous, multivariate spectrum, and as a binary diagnosis.&lt;p&gt;To be sure, clinically, thresholds are useful because services, insurance, and research all rely on clear binary classifications, in our current society. But outside that context, it isn’t obvious that everyday language needs to mirror that line. Self-identification can be a way of making sense of one’s life, not an attempt to claim a clinical label.&lt;p&gt;But at the same time, the spectrum includes people with very high support needs, and there’s understandable concern that broad or casual uses of the term can hide those realities in ways that impact care.&lt;p&gt;To me, none of this means people are wrong for wondering about autism. And I do not have the experience to advocate for or against &amp;quot;anxiety disorders&amp;quot; being weighted more heavily in clinicians&amp;#x27; priors than they currently are (as the OP article heavily implies with its length). I mean only to highlight the mismatch between a binary diagnostic system and a very heterogeneous spectrum, and the need for language that acknowledges self-understanding without flattening anyone’s experience.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.psychiatrymargins.com/p/autisms-confusing-cousins"&gt;www.psychiatrymargins.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172443"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>219</hn_points><hn_author>Anon84</hn_author><hn_order>18</hn_order></item><item><title>HTML as an Accessible Format for Papers</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173825</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173825</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:59:52 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If the Unicode consortium would spend less time and effort on emoji and more on making the most common&amp;#x2F;important mathematical symbols and notations available&amp;#x2F;renderable in plain text, maybe we could move past the (LA)TeX&amp;#x2F;PDF marriage. OpenType and TrueType now (edit: for well over a decade, actually) support the necessary conditional rendering required to perform complicated rendering operations to get sequences of Unicode code points to display in the way needed (theoretically, anyway) and with fallback missing-glyph-only font family substitution support available pretty much everywhere allowing you to seamlessly display symbols not in your primary font from a fallback asset (something like Noto, with every Unicode symbol supported by design, or math-specific fonts like Cambria Math or TeX Gyre, etc), there are no technical restrictions.&lt;p&gt;I’ve actually dug into this in the past and it was never lack of technical ability that prevented them from even adding just proper superscript&amp;#x2F;subscript support before, but rather their opinion that this didn’t belong in the symbolic layer. But since emoji abuse&amp;#x2F;rely on ZWJ and modifiers left and right to display in one of a myriad of variations, there’s really no good reason not to allow the same, because 2 and the squares symbol are not semantically the same (so it’s not a design choice).&lt;p&gt;An interesting (complete) tangent is that Gemini 3 Pro is the only model I’ve tested (I do a lot of math-related stuff with LLMs) that absolutely will not under any circumstances respect (system&amp;#x2F;user) prompt requests to avoid inline math mode (aka LATeX) in the output, regardless of whether I asked for a blanket ban on TeX&amp;#x2F;MathJax&amp;#x2F;etc or when I insisted that it use extended unicode codes points to substitute all math formula rendering (I primarily use LLMs via the TUI where I don’t have MathJax support, and as familiar as I once was with raw TeX mathematical notations and symbols, it’s still quite easy to confuse unrendered raw output by missing something if you’re not careful). I shared my experiment and results here – Gemini 3 Pro would insist on even rendering single letter constants or variables as $k$ instead of just k (or k in markdown italics, etc) no matter how hard I asked it not to (which makes me think it may have been overfit against raw LATeX papers, and is also an interesting argument in favor of the “VL LLMs are the more natural construct”):
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;NeoSmart&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1995582721327071367?s=20" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;NeoSmart&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1995582721327071367?s=20&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://info.arxiv.org/about/accessible_HTML.html"&gt;info.arxiv.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173825"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>198</hn_points><hn_author>el3ctron</hn_author><hn_order>13</hn_order></item><item><title>PalmOS on FisherPrice Pixter Toy</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170309</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170309</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 03:17:44 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was an intern at Fisher Price when they introduced the Pixter Color. I did QA on some of the games, the Dora one comes to mind. You can imagine the torture playing a level over and over.&lt;p&gt;The games were developed overseas (India I think?). I would send them bug reports in Mantis and overnight they would send a new build. Sometimes they would even fix the bugs. I would burn the builds on to EEPROMs and verify them the next day. The EEPROMS had a little round window so they could be erased in a UV box before programming.&lt;p&gt;Fisher Price used a video codec from Actimagine to fit video clips onto the game cartridges. That&amp;#x27;s how I learned about Virtualdub. I remember editing clips from a show called Winx.&lt;p&gt;The big competition was the Leapster LeapPad and they were trouncing us.&lt;p&gt;One fun thing the engineers did periodically was a toy teardown to see how competitors saved on cost. Cost was critical. They told me how Walmart basically dictates toy cost because they controlled the shelf space.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://dmitry.gr/?r=05.Projects&amp;proj=27.%20rePalm#pixter"&gt;dmitry.gr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170309"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>186</hn_points><hn_author>dmitrygr</hn_author><hn_order>42</hn_order></item><item><title>The unexpected effectiveness of one-shot decompilation with Claude</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080498</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080498</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:07:48 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;For anyone else who was initially confused by this, useful context is that Snowboard Kids 2 is an N64 game.&lt;p&gt;I also wasn&amp;#x27;t familiar with this terminology:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; You hand it a function; it tries to match it, and you move on.&lt;p&gt;In decompilation &amp;quot;matching&amp;quot; means you found a function block in the machine code, wrote some C, then confirmed that the C produces the exact same binary machine code once it is compiled.&lt;p&gt;The author&amp;#x27;s previous post explains this all in a bunch more detail: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.chrislewis.au&amp;#x2F;using-coding-agents-to-decompile-nintendo-64-games&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.chrislewis.au&amp;#x2F;using-coding-agents-to-decompile-...&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blog.chrislewis.au/the-unexpected-effectiveness-of-one-shot-decompilation-with-claude/"&gt;blog.chrislewis.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080498"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>176</hn_points><hn_author>knackers</hn_author><hn_order>28</hn_order></item><item><title>Touching the Elephant – TPUs</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172797</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172797</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 12:29:28 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Scaling ML textbook also has an excellent section on TPUs.
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jax-ml.github.io&amp;#x2F;scaling-book&amp;#x2F;tpus&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;jax-ml.github.io&amp;#x2F;scaling-book&amp;#x2F;tpus&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://considerthebulldog.com/tte-tpu/"&gt;considerthebulldog.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172797"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>155</hn_points><hn_author>giuliomagnifico</hn_author><hn_order>24</hn_order></item><item><title>Linux Instal Fest Belgrade</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172167</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172167</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 10:20:19 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I remember organizing Linux install parties at my university (University of Lille (1), in France), each year for like 3 to 4 consecutive years.&lt;p&gt;It was always a pleasure to meet new people and explain how basically &amp;quot;their computer is working&amp;quot; and how they can free from Windows.&lt;p&gt;The most interested person at that time was a 55 years old woman who knew nothing in computer. I installed Ubuntu on its computer and she came the next year with strong system knowledge for a linux-newbie, and the same laptop... with Debian in it!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://dmz.rs/lif2025_en"&gt;dmz.rs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172167"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>152</hn_points><hn_author>ubavic</hn_author><hn_order>30</hn_order></item><item><title>Making tiny 0.1cc two stroke engine from scratch</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46098655</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46098655</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 17:34:46 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I went down a rabbit hole lately and found this article on tiny diesel engines built throughout the past decades, most of them model engines: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;modelenginenews.org&amp;#x2F;techniques&amp;#x2F;minid.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;modelenginenews.org&amp;#x2F;techniques&amp;#x2F;minid.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I&amp;#x27;ve seen collectors turn a greenish blue and stammer out crazy offers on sight of my 0.1cc Nano, pictured here. But as the size goes down, construction difficulty and criticality of &amp;quot;fits&amp;quot; goes up exponentially.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/nKVq9u52A-c?si=KVY6AK7tsudqnbJN"&gt;youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46098655"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>145</hn_points><hn_author>pillars</hn_author><hn_order>43</hn_order></item><item><title>Screenshots from developers: 2002 vs. 2015 (2015)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46176905</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46176905</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 21:55:09 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;RMS could have taken a photo of his screen, or done something cheeky like dump his screen to a padded ASCII text file and submitted that. Stick in the mud.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://anders.unix.se/2015/12/10/screenshots-from-developers--2002-vs.-2015/"&gt;anders.unix.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46176905"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>139</hn_points><hn_author>turrini</hn_author></item><item><title>Kids who ran away to 1960s San Francisco</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123720</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123720</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:22:16 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I read Ulysses Grant&amp;#x27;s memoirs awhile back, and loved his description of being in San Francisco in the 1850s. (Another tidbit I loved is that he imagined an alternate path for his life where he would have settled down in the Bay Area and become a math teacher):&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The immigrant, on arriving, found himself a stranger, in a strange land, far from friends. Time pressed, for the little means that could be realized from the sale of what was left of the outfit would not support a man long at California prices. Many became discouraged. Others would take off their coats and look for a job, no matter what it might be. These succeeded as a rule. There were many young men who had studied professions before they went to California, and who had never done a day&amp;#x27;s manual labor in their lives, who took in the situation at once and went to work to make a start at anything they could get to do. Some supplied carpenters and masons with material—carrying plank, brick, or mortar, as the case might be; others drove stages, drays, or baggage wagons, until they could do better. More became discouraged early and spent their time looking up people who would &amp;#x27;treat,&amp;#x27; or lounging about restaurants and gambling houses where free lunches were furnished daily.&amp;quot;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.fieldnotes.nautilus.quest/p/the-kids-who-ran-away-to-1960s-san"&gt;www.fieldnotes.nautilus.quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123720"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>134</hn_points><hn_author>zackoverflow</hn_author><hn_order>32</hn_order></item></channel></rss>