<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:06:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Size of Life</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:02:57 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hi all! I’m Aleix Ramon, the music composer of the soundtrack.&lt;p&gt;Since some of you asked, here’s the soundtrack on Bandcamp: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aleixramon.bandcamp.com&amp;#x2F;album&amp;#x2F;size-of-life-original-soundtrack" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;aleixramon.bandcamp.com&amp;#x2F;album&amp;#x2F;size-of-life-original-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;There you can download it in high quality, and it’s a pay-what-you-want: you can get it for free if you want, or pay what you feel like and support me. Either way, I’m happy that you enjoy it!&lt;p&gt;The music should also be on Spotify, Apple Music, and most music streaming services within the next 24h.&lt;p&gt;A bit about the process of scoring Size of Life:&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with Neal before on a couple of his other games, including Absurd Trolley Problems, so we were used to working together (and with his producer—you’re awesome, Liz!). When Neal told me about Size of Life, we had an inspiring conversation about how the music could make the players feel.&lt;p&gt;The core idea was that it should enhance that feeling of wondrous discovery, but subtly, without taking the attention away from the beautiful illustrations.&lt;p&gt;I also thought it should reflect the organisms&amp;#x27; increasing size—as some of you pointed out, the music grows with them. I think of it as a single instrument that builds upon itself, like the cells in an increasingly complex organism. So I composed 12 layers that loop indefinitely—as you progress, each layer is added, and as you go back, they’re subtracted. The effect is most clear if you get to the end and then return to the smaller organisms!&lt;p&gt;Since the game has an encyclopedia vibe to it, I proposed to go with a string instrument to give it a subtle “Enlightenment-era” and “cultural” feel. I was suspecting the cello could be a good instrument because of its range and expressivity.&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, the next week I met the cellist Iratxe Ibaibarriaga at a game conference in Barcelona, where I’m based, and she immediately became the ideal person for it. She’s done a wonderful job bringing a ton of expressivity to the playing, and it’s been a delight to work with her.&lt;p&gt;I got very excited when Neal told me he was making an educational game—I come from a family of school teachers. I’ve been scoring games for over 10 years, but this is the first educational game I’ve scored.&lt;p&gt;In a way, now the circle feels complete!&lt;p&gt;(if anyone wants to reach out, feel free to do so! You can find me and all my stuff here: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aleixramon.com&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.aleixramon.com&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt; )&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://neal.fun/size-of-life/"&gt;neal.fun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219346"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>2425</hn_points><hn_author>eatonphil</hn_author><hn_order>29</hn_order></item><item><title>Getting a Gemini API key is an exercise in frustration</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223311</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223311</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:29:12 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey! Very valid feedback on setting up a billing account. This is something I have been pushing for over the last 2 years at Google. The good news: setting up billing directly in AI Studio tested internally and will be shipped in January : )&lt;p&gt;Will follow up on some of the other threads in here!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://ankursethi.com/blog/gemini-api-key-frustration/"&gt;ankursethi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223311"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>770</hn_points><hn_author>speckx</hn_author><hn_order>18</hn_order></item><item><title>Auto-grading decade-old Hacker News discussions with hindsight</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:23:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;Related from yesterday: &lt;i&gt;Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 imagines the HN front page 10 years from now&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46205632&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;#x27;s fun to read some of these historic comments! A while back I wrote a replay system to better capture how discussions evolved at the time of these historic threads. Here&amp;#x27;s Karpathy&amp;#x27;s list from his graded articles, in the replay visualizer:&lt;p&gt;Swift is Open Source
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10669891" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10669891&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launch of Figma, a collaborative interface design tool
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10685407" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10685407&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introducing OpenAI
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10720176" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10720176&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first person to hack the iPhone is building a self-driving car
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10744206" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10744206&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;SpaceX launch webcast: Orbcomm-2 Mission [video]
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10774865" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10774865&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Theranos, Many Strategies and Snags
&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10799261" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;hn.unlurker.com&amp;#x2F;replay?item=10799261&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://karpathy.bearblog.dev/auto-grade-hn/"&gt;karpathy.bearblog.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220540"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>538</hn_points><hn_author>__rito__</hn_author><hn_order>14</hn_order></item><item><title>Patterns.dev</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226483</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226483</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 01:18:55 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Design patterns can be really helpful. In my previous job I worked on enterprise .NET applications. It made sense to use common patterns, because most applications were big and the patterns made it easier to understand unfamiliar code, within an application but also across different teams and applications. New projects looked familiar, because the same style and the same patterns were used.&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#x27;m working on an old (+10 years) JS application. Similar patterns were implemented, but in this case it&amp;#x27;s not helpful at all. The code looks very corporate and Java EE style, with a ton of getters and setters (`getName() {}`, not `get name() {}`, factories, facades, adapters, etc, etc. It&amp;#x27;s usually completely unclear what the benefit of the pattern is, and code is more complicated, for instance because creating new instances of business objects is split into `Object.build` which calls `new Object`, with no guidelines at all what part of the initialization should be in `build` and what should be in the constructor.&lt;p&gt;The gist of my comment is that patterns can be useful, but usually they&amp;#x27;re overused and if you implement one without understanding why and without benefiting from faster understanding the code because the pattern is applied consistently over multiple instances, the result is worse than just implementing what you need in a readable way (YAGNI).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.patterns.dev/"&gt;www.patterns.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226483"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>517</hn_points><hn_author>handfuloflight</hn_author><hn_order>19</hn_order></item><item><title>Rubio stages font coup: Times New Roman ousts Calibri</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212438</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212438</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:08:34 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.md&amp;#x2F;x0Sxc" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.md&amp;#x2F;x0Sxc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our studio, LucasFonts, designed Calibri. Here are our CEO Luc(as) de Groot’s thoughts on the matter:&lt;p&gt;The decision to abandon Calibri on the grounds of it being a so-called “wasteful diversity font” is both amusing and regrettable. Calibri was specifically designed to enhance readability on modern computer screens and was selected by Microsoft in 2007 to replace Times New Roman as the default font in the Office suite. There were sound reasons for moving away from Times: Calibri performs exceptionally well at small sizes and on standard office monitors, whereas serif fonts like Times New Roman tend to appear more distorted. While serif fonts are well-suited to high-resolution displays, such as those found on modern smartphones, on typical office screens the serifs introduce unnecessary visual noise and can be particularly problematic for users with impaired vision, such as older adults.&lt;p&gt;Professional typography can be achieved with both serif and sans-serif fonts. However, Times New Roman—a typeface older than the current president—presents unique challenges. Originally crafted in Great Britain for newspaper printing, Times was optimised for paper, with each letterform meticulously cut and tested for specific sizes. In the digital era, larger size drawings were repurposed as models, resulting in a typeface that appears too thin and sharp when printed at high quality.&lt;p&gt;Serif fonts are often perceived as more traditional, but they are also more demanding to use effectively. While a skilled typographer can, in theory, produce excellent results with Times, using it in its default digital form is not considered professional practice.&lt;p&gt;Calibri, by contrast, incorporates extensive spacing adjustments and language-specific refinements. The digital version of Times New Roman, developed in the early days of computing, offers only minimal kerning and letter-pair adjustments. This is especially evident in words set in all capitals—such as “CHICAGO”—where the spacing is inconsistent: the letters “HIC” are tightly packed, while “CAG” are spaced too far apart. Microsoft cannot rectify these issues without altering the appearance of existing documents.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/rubio-stages-font-coup-times-new-roman-ousts-calibri-2025-12-09/"&gt;www.reuters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212438"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>375</hn_points><hn_author>italophil</hn_author><hn_order>39</hn_order></item><item><title>How Google Maps allocates survival across London's restaurants</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203343</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203343</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:20:02 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;#x27;s always annoyed me that zooming in on a building will not reliably show the business that operates there. I understand that at low zoom levels you may need to filter what is displayed based on the high density, but when I zoom in I want to see everything that is there. Sometimes I am forced to go to street view to read the sign, then type the company name into the search box to force the business marker to show up and get clickable.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve found Apple Maps is a little better in this regard. They show a higher density of business markers at any given zoom level.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://laurenleek.substack.com/p/how-google-maps-quietly-allocates"&gt;laurenleek.substack.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203343"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>368</hn_points><hn_author>justincormack</hn_author><hn_order>35</hn_order></item><item><title>Disney making $1B investment in OpenAI, will allow characters on Sora AI</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231585</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231585</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 14:12:14 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This will not end well for Disney, there were certain historical characters removed from Sora 2 because people kept making racist videos that are hard to censor, and it became increasingly unhinged. This feels like another circular investment where Disney is hoping to make money back I&amp;#x27;m sure. On the other hand, assuming they do the freemium stuff, I look forward to making a few videos of my daughters favorite Disney princesses &amp;quot;talking&amp;quot; to her.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/12/11/disney-openai-sora-characters-video.html"&gt;www.cnbc.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46231585"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>310</hn_points><hn_author>tiahura</hn_author><hn_order>34</hn_order></item><item><title>GPT-5.2</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234788</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234788</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:04:47 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;platform.openai.com&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;guides&amp;#x2F;latest-model" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;platform.openai.com&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;guides&amp;#x2F;latest-model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;System card: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;cdn.openai.com&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;3a4153c8-c748-4b71-8e31-aecbde944f8d&amp;#x2F;oai_5_2_system-card.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;cdn.openai.com&amp;#x2F;pdf&amp;#x2F;3a4153c8-c748-4b71-8e31-aecbde944...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#x27;ve benchmarked it on the Extended NYT Connections benchmark (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;lechmazur&amp;#x2F;nyt-connections&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;lechmazur&amp;#x2F;nyt-connections&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;p&gt;The high-reasoning version of GPT-5.2 improves on GPT-5.1: 69.9 → 77.9.&lt;p&gt;The medium-reasoning version also improves: 62.7 → 72.1.&lt;p&gt;The no-reasoning version also improves: 22.1 → 27.5.&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 Pro and Grok 4.1 Fast Reasoning still score higher.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-2/"&gt;openai.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46234788"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>308</hn_points><hn_author>atgctg</hn_author></item><item><title>Qwen3-Omni-Flash-2025-12-01：a next-generation native multimodal large model</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219538</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219538</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 16:13:38 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is a 30B parameter MoE with 3B active parameters and is the successor to their previous 7B omni model. [1]&lt;p&gt;You can expect this model to have similar performance to the non-omni version. [2]&lt;p&gt;There aren&amp;#x27;t many open-weights omni models so I consider this a big deal. I would use this model to replace the keyboard and monitor in an application while doing the heavy lifting with other tech behind the scenes. There is also a reasoning version, which might be a bit amusing in an interactive voice chat if it pronounces the thinking tokens while working through to a final answer.&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;huggingface.co&amp;#x2F;Qwen&amp;#x2F;Qwen2.5-Omni-7B" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;huggingface.co&amp;#x2F;Qwen&amp;#x2F;Qwen2.5-Omni-7B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;artificialanalysis.ai&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;qwen3-30b-a3b-instruct" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;artificialanalysis.ai&amp;#x2F;models&amp;#x2F;qwen3-30b-a3b-instruct&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://qwen.ai/blog?id=qwen3-omni-flash-20251201"&gt;qwen.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46219538"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>300</hn_points><hn_author>pretext</hn_author><hn_order>43</hn_order></item><item><title>Show HN: I've asked Claude to improve codebase quality 200 times</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197930</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197930</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 21:33:09 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Claude is really good at specific analysis, but really terrible at open-ended problems.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hey claude, I get this error message: &amp;lt;X&amp;gt;&amp;quot;, and it&amp;#x27;ll often find the root cause quicker than I could.&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hey claude, anything I could do to improve Y?&amp;quot;, and it&amp;#x27;ll struggle beyond the basics that a linter might suggest.&lt;p&gt;It suggested enthusiastically a library for &amp;lt;work domain&amp;gt; and it was all &amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;Recommended&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot; about it, but when I pointed out that the library had been considered and rejected because &amp;lt;issue&amp;gt;, it understood and wrote up why that library suffered from that issue and why it was therefore unsuitable.&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#x27;s a significant blind-spot in current LLMs related to blue-sky thinking and creative problem solving. It can do structured problems very well, and it can transform unstructured data very well, but it can&amp;#x27;t deal with unstructured problems very well.&lt;p&gt;That may well change, so I don&amp;#x27;t want to embed that thought too deeply into my own priors, because the LLM space seems to evolve rapidly. I wouldn&amp;#x27;t want to find myself blind to the progress because I write it off from a class of problems.&lt;p&gt;But right now, the best way to help an LLM is have a deep understanding of the problem domain yourself, and just leverage it to do the grunt-work that you&amp;#x27;d find boring.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://gricha.dev/blog/the-highest-quality-codebase"&gt;gricha.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197930"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>299</hn_points><hn_author>Gricha</hn_author><hn_order>9</hn_order></item><item><title>iPhone Typos? It's Not Just You – The iOS Keyboard Is Broken [video]</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232528</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232528</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:25:43 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have had this conversation with several people. I feel like I used to be able to type with a fairly low error rate on a smaller screen with old iPhones. Now I feel that it is constant exercise in frustration as I will hit a letter and the keyboard will decide to pick the letter next to it. It is evolving backwards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hksVvXONrIo"&gt;www.youtube.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232528"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>291</hn_points><hn_author>walterbell</hn_author><hn_order>40</hn_order></item><item><title>Super Mario 64 for the PS1</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221925</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221925</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:58:55 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you like this port, you may also enjoy this ground-up effort to clone SM64 on the GBA &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;nS5rj80L-pk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;youtu.be&amp;#x2F;nS5rj80L-pk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/malucard/sm64-psx"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221925"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>281</hn_points><hn_author>LaserDiscMan</hn_author><hn_order>41</hn_order></item><item><title>Booting Linux in QEMU and Writing PID 1 in Go to Illustrate Kernel as Program</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46147987</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46147987</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:25:38 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nice article! One point of clarification:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; When the kernel starts it does not have all of the parts loaded that are needed to access the disks in the computer, so it needs a filesystem loaded into the memory called initramfs (Initial RAM filesystem).&lt;p&gt;The kernel &lt;i&gt;might&lt;/i&gt; not have all the parts needed to mount the filesystem, especially on a modern Linux distro that supports a wide variety of hardware.&lt;p&gt;Initramfs exists so that parts of the boot logic can be handled in userspace. Part of this includes deciding which device drivers to load as kernel modules, using something like udev.&lt;p&gt;Another part is deciding &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; root filesystem to mount. The root FS might be on an LVM volume that needs to be configured with device-mapper, or unlocked with decrypt. Or it might be mounted over a network, which in turn requires IP configuration and authentication. You don&amp;#x27;t want the kernel to have those mechanisms hard-coded, so initramfs allows handling them in userspace.&lt;p&gt;But strictly speaking, you don&amp;#x27;t &lt;i&gt;need&lt;/i&gt; any of that for a minimal system. You can boot without initramfs at all, as long as no special userspace setup is required. i.e., the root FS is a plain old disk partition specified on the kernel command line, and the correct drivers (e.g. for a SCSI&amp;#x2F;SATA hard drive) are already linked into the kernel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://serversfor.dev/linux-inside-out/the-linux-kernel-is-just-a-program/"&gt;serversfor.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46147987"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>241</hn_points><hn_author>birdculture</hn_author><hn_order>32</hn_order></item><item><title>Show HN: Automated license plate reader coverage in the USA</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220794</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220794</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:42:30 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;Built this over the last few days, based on a Rust codebase that parses the latest ALPR reports from OpenStreetMaps, calculates navigation statistics from every tagged residential building to nearby amenities, and tests each route for intersection with those ALPR cameras (Flock being the most widespread).&lt;p&gt;These have gotten more controversial in recent months, due to their indiscriminate large scale data collection, with 404 Media publishing many original pieces (&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.404media.co&amp;#x2F;tag&amp;#x2F;flock&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.404media.co&amp;#x2F;tag&amp;#x2F;flock&amp;#x2F;&lt;/a&gt;) about their adoption and (ab)use across the country. I wanted to use open source datasets to track the rapid expansion, especially per-county, as this data can be crucial for &amp;#x27;deflock&amp;#x27; movements to petition counties and city governments to ban and remove them.&lt;p&gt;In some counties, the tracking becomes so widespread that most people can&amp;#x27;t go anywhere without being photographed. This includes possibly sensitive areas, like places of worship and medical facilities.&lt;p&gt;The argument for their legality rests upon the notion that these cameras are equivalent to &amp;#x27;mere observation&amp;#x27;, but the enormous scope and data sharing agreements in place to share and access &lt;i&gt;millions&lt;/i&gt; of records without warrants blurs the lines of the fourth amendment.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;#x27;ve thought about this a lot as I see more and more reckless driving in the areas I live in. Surveillance is generally a net negative, but it&amp;#x27;s also bad when you see people speeding around schools, rolling through stop signs, and running red lights. We seem to have a worst of all situations where traffic is getting increasingly difficult to enforce, driving is getting more dangerous year by year, and we&amp;#x27;re terrified of government overreach if we add any automation at all to enforcement.&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#x27;t know the solution, but I do know that in the US we&amp;#x27;ve lost 10-15 years of progress when it comes to traffic fatalities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://alpranalysis.com"&gt;alpranalysis.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220794"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>227</hn_points><hn_author>sodality2</hn_author><hn_order>44</hn_order></item><item><title>Helldivers 2 on-disk size 85% reduction</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131518</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131518</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:08:31 +0000</pubDate><description>
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid #ccc; background-color:#f9f9f9; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The negativity towards this is wild. A company followed relatively widely accepted industry practice (lots and lots of other games also have huge sizes on disk for the exact same reason), then eventually they decided to do their own independent testing to check whether said common practice actually makes things better or not in their case, found that it didn&amp;#x27;t, so they reversed it. In addition, they wrote up some nice technical articles on the topic, helping to change the old accepted industry wisdom.&lt;p&gt;This seems great to me. Am I crazy? This feels like it should be Hacker News&amp;#x27;s bread and butter, articles about &amp;quot;we moved away from Kubernetes&amp;#x2F;microservices&amp;#x2F;node.js&amp;#x2F;serverless&amp;#x2F;React because we did our own investigation and found that the upsides aren&amp;#x27;t worth the downsides&amp;quot; tend to do really well here. How is this received so differently?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/news/app/553850/view/491583942944621371"&gt;store.steampowered.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131518"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>207</hn_points><hn_author>SergeAx</hn_author><hn_order>24</hn_order></item></channel></rss>