<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News Top Stories</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/</link><description>Top stories from Hacker News</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 15:04:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367224</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367224</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:33:42 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/bellard/mquickjs/blob/main/README.md"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;If this had been available in 2010, Redis scripting would have been JavaScript and not Lua. Lua was chosen based on the implementation requirements, not on the language ones... (small, fast, ANSI-C). I appreciate certain ideas in Lua, and people love it, but I was never able to &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; Lua, because it departs from a more Algol-like syntax and semantics without good reasons, for my taste. This creates friction for newcomers. I love friction when it opens new useful ideas and abstractions that are worth it, if you learn SmallTalk or FORTH and for some time you are lost, it&amp;#x27;s part of how the languages are different. But I think for Lua this is not true enough: it feels like it departs from what people know without good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 1479 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; Aissen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367224"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>1479</hn_points><hn_author>Aissen</hn_author><hn_order>55</hn_order></item><item><title>Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392115</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392115</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:08:47 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://skyview.social/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fbsky.app%2Fprofile%2Frobpike.io%2Fpost%2F3matwg6w3ic2s&amp;viewtype=tree"&gt;skyview.social&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Related: &lt;i&gt;Rob Pike got spammed with an AI slop &amp;quot;act of kindness&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46394867"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=46394867&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I don’t really understand the hate he gets over this. If you want to thank someone for their contribution, do that yourself? Sending thank you from an ML model is anything but respectful. I can only imagine that if I got a message like that I’d be furious too.&lt;p&gt;This reminds me a story from my mom’s work from years ago: the company she was working for announced salary increases to each worker individually. Some, like my mom, got a little bit more, but some got a monthly increase around 2 PLN (about $0.5). At that point, it feels like a slap in the face. A thank you from AI gives the same vibe.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 1421 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; christoph-heiss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392115"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>1421</hn_points><hn_author>christoph-heiss</hn_author><hn_order>42</hn_order></item><item><title>How uv got so fast</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46393992</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46393992</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:13:07 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://nesbitt.io/2025/12/26/how-uv-got-so-fast.html"&gt;nesbitt.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;The most surprising part of uv&amp;#x27;s success to me isn&amp;#x27;t Rust at all, it&amp;#x27;s how much speed we &amp;quot;unlocked&amp;quot; just by finally treating Python packaging as a well-specified systems problem instead of a pile of historical accidents. If uv had been written in Go or even highly optimized CPython, but with the same design decisions (PEP 517&amp;#x2F;518&amp;#x2F;621&amp;#x2F;658 focus, HTTP range tricks, aggressive wheel-first strategy, ignoring obviously defensive upper bounds, etc.), I strongly suspect we&amp;#x27;d be debating a 1.3× vs 1.5× speedup instead of a 10× headline — but the conversation here keeps collapsing back to &amp;quot;Rust rewrite good&amp;#x2F;bad.&amp;quot; That feels like cargo-culting the toolchain instead of asking the uncomfortable question: why did it take a greenfield project to give Python the package manager behavior people clearly wanted for the last decade?&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 1042 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; zdw&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46393992"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>1042</hn_points><hn_author>zdw</hn_author><hn_order>4</hn_order></item><item><title>Maybe the default settings are too high</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387657</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387657</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:13:21 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.raptitude.com/2025/12/maybe-the-default-settings-are-too-high/"&gt;www.raptitude.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;My dad was a busy construction contractor. One summer he tore himself away from work and took the family to a week long boat camp out next to a big beautiful lake. It turned out that our campsite was actually in the lake by a few inches at high water, but dad saw a way to dam it off and keep it dry, so he grabs the shovel and starts digging trenches and building walls and ordering us around.&lt;p&gt;About an hour into that, pouring sweat, he stops cold and says &amp;quot;what the hell am I doing?&amp;quot; The flooded camp was actually nice on a hot day and all we really had to do was move a couple of tents. He dropped the shovel and spent the rest of the week sunbathing, fishing, snorkeling and water skiing as God intended. He flipped a switch and went from Hyde to Jekyll on vacation. I&amp;#x27;ve had to emulate that a few times.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 898 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; htk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387657"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>898</hn_points><hn_author>htk</hn_author><hn_order>53</hn_order></item><item><title>Package managers keep using Git as a database, it never works out</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391514</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391514</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:46:36 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://nesbitt.io/2025/12/24/package-managers-keep-using-git-as-a-database.html"&gt;nesbitt.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;This seems like a tragedy of the commons -- GitHub is free after all, and it has all of these great properties, so why not? -- but this kind of decision making occurs whenever externalities are present.&lt;p&gt;My favorite hill to die on (externality) is user time.  Most software houses spend so much time focusing on how expensive engineering time is that they neglect user time.  Software houses optimize for feature delivery and not user interaction time.  Yet if I spent one hour making my app one second faster for my million users, I can save 277 user hour per year. But since user hours are an externality, such optimization never gets done.&lt;p&gt;Externalities lead to users downloading extra gigabytes of data (wasted time) and waiting for software, all of which is waste that the developer isn&amp;#x27;t responsible for and doesn&amp;#x27;t care about.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 692 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; birdculture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391514"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>692</hn_points><hn_author>birdculture</hn_author><hn_order>16</hn_order></item><item><title>FFmpeg has issued a DMCA takedown on GitHub</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394327</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394327</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:48:25 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FFmpeg/status/2004599109559496984"&gt;twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;The repo in question incorporated FFmpeg code while claiming their code is Apache 2.0-licensed over 1.5 years ago[1]&lt;p&gt;This is not allowed under the LGPL, which mandates dynamic linking against the library. They copy-pasted FFmpeg code into their repo instead.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;HermanChen1982&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1761230920563233137" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;x.com&amp;#x2F;HermanChen1982&amp;#x2F;status&amp;#x2F;1761230920563233137&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 503 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; merlindru&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394327"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>503</hn_points><hn_author>merlindru</hn_author><hn_order>40</hn_order></item><item><title>My insulin pump controller uses the Linux kernel. It also violates the GPL</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395184</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395184</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 19:13:22 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1puojsr/the_device_that_controls_my_insulin_pump_uses_the/"&gt;old.reddit.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;i&gt;I then decided to contact Insulet to get the kernel source code for it, being GPLv2 licensed, they&amp;#x27;re obligated to provide it.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is technically not true.  It is an oversimplification of the common case, but what actually normally should happen is that:&lt;p&gt;1. The GPL requires the company to send the user a &lt;i&gt;written offer&lt;/i&gt; of source code.&lt;p&gt;2. The user uses this offer to request the source code from the company.&lt;p&gt;3. If the user does not receive the source code, the user can sue the company for not honoring its promises, i.e. the offer of source code.  This is not a GPL violation; it is a straight contract violation; the contract in this case being the explicit offer of source code, and not the GPL.&lt;p&gt;Note that all this is completely off the rails if the user does not receive a written offer of source code in the first place.  In this case, the user has no right to source code, since the user did not receive an offer for source code.&lt;p&gt;However, the copyright holders can immediately sue the company for violating the GPL, since the company did not send a written offer of source code to the user.  It does not matter if the company does or does not send the source code to the user; the fact that the company did not send a written offer to the user in the first place is by itself a GPL violation.&lt;p&gt;(IANAL)&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 450 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; davisr&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395184"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>450</hn_points><hn_author>davisr</hn_author><hn_order>35</hn_order></item><item><title>Experts explore new mushroom which causes fairytale-like hallucinations</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46393936</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46393936</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:07:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://nhmu.utah.edu/articles/experts-explore-new-mushroom-which-causes-fairytale-hallucinations"&gt;nhmu.utah.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.is&amp;#x2F;CwDtf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;archive.is&amp;#x2F;CwDtf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;So, about one mushroom species in five is poisonous. Why is the ratio so low, why are there lots of edible ones? Without hard-shelled seeds to spread, why be eaten? And the poisonous ones apparently don&amp;#x27;t use color as a warning signal, and don&amp;#x27;t smell all that bad, and some of the poisons have really mild effects, like &amp;quot;gives only some people diarrhea&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;makes a hangover worse&amp;quot;. Meanwhile three of the deadliest species seemed to need their toxin (amanitin) so much that they picked it up through &lt;i&gt;horizontal gene transfer.&lt;/i&gt; Why did just &lt;i&gt;those&lt;/i&gt; ones need to be deadly? In addition to which we have these species that don&amp;#x27;t even make you sick, just make you trip out, a function which looks to have evolved three times over in different ways. What kind of half-assed evolutionary strategies are these? What do mushrooms &lt;i&gt;want?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 427 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; astronads&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46393936"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>427</hn_points><hn_author>astronads</hn_author><hn_order>18</hn_order></item><item><title>Toys with the highest play-time and lowest clean-up-time</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395885</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395885</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:28:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://joannabregan.substack.com/p/toys-with-the-highest-play-time-and"&gt;joannabregan.substack.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;The set of toys I spent the most time playing with was a big bag of wooden blocks my grandfather gave me when I was very small. They are well designed, with a good selection of different shapes, e.g. it has cylinders and arches and thin planks as well as cuboids. They got a lot of use because they&amp;#x27;re so flexible in combining with other toys, e.g. you can build roads and garages for toy cars, or obstacle courses for rolling marbles. The edges and corners are rounded and the wood tough enough that clean-up was just dropping them back into the bag.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve since given them to a nephew and I&amp;#x27;m happy to see he gets just as much entertainment out of them as I did. Plain wooden blocks can represent almost anything. There are no batteries or moving parts to fail. Mine got a little bit of surface wear but they still work just as well as they did when they were new and small children don&amp;#x27;t care about perfect appearance. I wouldn&amp;#x27;t be surprised if they end up getting passed down to another generation and continue to provide the same entertainment. I highly recommend this kind of simple toy for young children.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 423 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; surprisetalk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395885"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>423</hn_points><hn_author>surprisetalk</hn_author><hn_order>34</hn_order></item><item><title>Show HN: Witr – Explain why a process is running on your Linux system</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392910</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392910</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:20:36 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/pranshuparmar/witr"&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi HN,&lt;p&gt;I built a small Linux CLI tool called witr (Why Is This Running?).&lt;p&gt;The idea came from a situation most of us have hit: you log into a machine, see a process or port running, and immediately wonder why it exists, who started it, and what is keeping it alive right now.&lt;p&gt;witr traces a process, service, or port back to its origin and responsibility chain and explains it in a way that’s quick to read, especially when you’re debugging under pressure.&lt;p&gt;This is v0.1.0. It’s intentionally small and focused.
Feedback, criticism, and edge cases are very welcome.&lt;p&gt;Repo: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;pranshuparmar&amp;#x2F;witr" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;github.com&amp;#x2F;pranshuparmar&amp;#x2F;witr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;This is great. Small, trivial suggestion: the gif that loops in the README should pause on the screen w&amp;#x2F; the output for a few seconds longer - it disappears (restarts) too quickly to take in all of the output.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 385 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; pranshuparmar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392910"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>385</hn_points><hn_author>pranshuparmar</hn_author><hn_order>23</hn_order></item><item><title>The best things and stuff of 2025</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365726</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365726</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:51:33 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://blog.fogus.me/2025/12/23/the-best-things-and-stuff-of-2025.html"&gt;blog.fogus.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;That 1956 article on the long-distance telephone network is fascinating reading.&lt;p&gt;The chart on page 24 gives the very first division of the US phone into area codes, many of which have of course remained unchanged today.&lt;p&gt;From page 82, when discussing automated in-band signaling on the phone lines:&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; The signal component is a band about 100 cycles [Hz] wide centering on the signal frequency [2600 Hz]. [...] In the talking condition (tone off in both directions) the guard detector sensitivity is such that almost a pure tone is required to operate the receiver since other than signal frequencies will produce a voltage opposing its operation. The guard feature prevents false operation of the receiver from speech signals.&lt;p&gt;Of course in hindsight, the flaw in this is obvious. The guard band prevents &lt;i&gt;accidental&lt;/i&gt; triggering of the signal mechanism by ordinary speech. It does nothing to stop someone from &lt;i&gt;intentionally&lt;/i&gt; playing a pure 2600 Hz tone into the telephone handset, using e.g. a whistle from a cereal box.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 314 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; adityaathalye&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365726"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>314</hn_points><hn_author>adityaathalye</hn_author><hn_order>13</hn_order></item><item><title>Exe.dev</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397609</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397609</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 23:42:46 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://exe.dev/"&gt;exe.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.exe.dev&amp;#x2F;meet-exe.dev" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;blog.exe.dev&amp;#x2F;meet-exe.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;exe.dev&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;how-exedev-works" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;exe.dev&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;how-exedev-works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;exe.dev&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;pricing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;exe.dev&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;pricing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;That must be worst website ever made.&lt;p&gt;Zero information available on mobile.&lt;p&gt;I thought it is some kind of portfolio site that does not work on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 312 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; achairapart&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397609"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>312</hn_points><hn_author>achairapart</hn_author><hn_order>10</hn_order></item><item><title>Always bet on text (2014)</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397379</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397379</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 23:09:40 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://graydon2.dreamwidth.org/193447.html"&gt;graydon2.dreamwidth.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I have mixed feelings about this. On the one hand, I agree: text is infinitely versatile, indexable, durable, etc. But, after discovering Bret Victor&amp;#x27;s work[1], and thinking about how I learned piano, I&amp;#x27;ve also started to see a lot of the limitations of text. When I learned piano, I always had a live feedback loop: play a note, and hear how it sounds, and every week I had a teacher coach me. This is a completely different way to learn a skill, and something that doesn&amp;#x27;t work well with text.&lt;p&gt;Bret Victor&amp;#x27;s point is why is this not also the approach we use for other topics, like engineering? There are many people who do not have a strong symbolic intuition, and so being able to tap into their (and our) other intuitions is a very powerful tool to increase efficiency of communication. More and more, I have found myself in this alternate philosophy of education and knowledge transmission. There are certainly limits—and text isn&amp;#x27;t going anywhere, but I think there&amp;#x27;s still a lot more to discover and try.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dynamicland.org&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;The_Humane_Representation_of_Thought&amp;#x2F;" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dynamicland.org&amp;#x2F;2014&amp;#x2F;The_Humane_Representation_of_Th...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 279 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; jesseduffield&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397379"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>279</hn_points><hn_author>jesseduffield</hn_author><hn_order>11</hn_order></item><item><title>Ask HN: What did you read in 2025?</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391572</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391572</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:55:16 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391572"&gt;news.ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mostly read newspapers and technical journals, but two books that I read that made an impression: &amp;quot;The Changing World Order&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;The Gulag Archipelago&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Mary Renault. &lt;i&gt;Fire From Heaven.&lt;/i&gt; I think she was ahead of the curve in recognizing that Alexander had monstrous qualities at a time when he was still seen as a kind of superhero.&lt;p&gt;Tolkein. &lt;i&gt;The Silmarillion.&lt;/i&gt; I’ve bounced off this book a dozen times over decades, despite deeply enjoying &lt;i&gt;The Hobbit&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;LoTR&lt;/i&gt;. This time I discovered that the best way to read it is backwards, tracing connections to characters you already know.&lt;p&gt;Stephenson. &lt;i&gt;Anathem&lt;/i&gt;. I think I’ll skip the end next time. The first time I read it, I was confused; this time I understood exactly what was happening but I thought it was a bit pointless. Still worth it for the first 3&amp;#x2F;4 of the novel.&lt;p&gt;Lots of short stories. I was expecting to like Mark Twain better, but ours is a much more earnest era, and no match for his Gilded Age cynicism. What passes for cynicism today is Twain in his sunniest mood. At any rate, I appreciate Twain, but I enjoy EM Forster, Henry James, JG Ballard, William Gibson, and lots of others I’m forgetting at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 252 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; kwar13&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391572"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>252</hn_points><hn_author>kwar13</hn_author><hn_order>32</hn_order></item><item><title>LearnixOS</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391599</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391599</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 12:59:56 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.learnix-os.com"&gt;www.learnix-os.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;From the name I thought this was about learning NixOS, and they found a very clever name&lt;p&gt;Maybe the author could add a small note that this is not about that, and refer to something official about NixOS?&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I like the idea of the project!&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 246 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; gtirloni&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391599"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>246</hn_points><hn_author>gtirloni</hn_author><hn_order>29</hn_order></item><item><title>Ask HN: What skills do you want to develop or improve in 2026?</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385197</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385197</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 16:08:57 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385197"&gt;news.ycombinator.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thread for 2025: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=42509408"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=42509408&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thread for 2024: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=38782613"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=38782613&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thread for 2023: &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=33873800"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;news.ycombinator.com&amp;#x2F;item?id=33873800&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are mine:&lt;p&gt;Technical skills:&lt;p&gt;- Among my last year&amp;#x27;s goals was to take on VR dev, which sadly I did not get to. Punting it to 2026. I&amp;#x27;m thinking to get the Samsung Galaxy XR and experiment with some VR apps and learn the fundamentals of spatial computing. As an Android mobile developer, that feels like a natural extension.&lt;p&gt;- Complete the &amp;quot;UCSanDiegoX: Computer Graphics II: Rendering&amp;quot; computer graphics course. I did the first course in the series and found it enlightening (no pun intended)&lt;p&gt;- Create an e2e project that earns money as a side gig. It&amp;#x27;s time to put my product and technical knowledge to practice and actually build something people want.&lt;p&gt;- Leverage AI across all my endeavors. AI tools are here to stay and the more I know how to use them effectively, the better. The speed boost in learning a new framework&amp;#x2F;concept is phenomenal.&lt;p&gt;Non-technical skills:&lt;p&gt;- Expand my social circle - the unstable tech climate made me realize the importance of maintaining a healthy social network. My goal is to connect with more people both inside my company and outside, by both proactively reaching out and going to meetups in my area. In fact, I invite fellow NYC-based HN-ers to contact me at cybercreampuff at yahoo dot com, in case you want to meet up!&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;This is a new years resolution question barely in disguise, but they&amp;#x27;re fun cause a lot of us are cooped up, barely 4 days into winter, 86ish to go, and we&amp;#x27;re champing at the bit for change.&lt;p&gt;I am pretty sure I&amp;#x27;m a 50th percentiler. I&amp;#x27;m mid 40s, kinda burned out but still struggling forward in my ok-but-not-hollywood IT career, I still have a passion for doing things well in a technical society that values doing things cheap (and well). The things I am known for being good at, I still google daily, and for a long time, I&amp;#x27;ve been hungry for a change - any change - but especially one that isn&amp;#x27;t chaotically negative.&lt;p&gt;So in 2026, I wanna learn how dirt works.&lt;p&gt;I actually have a giant box of dirt sitting on a shelf at the UNH community co-op soil analysis lab, waiting to give me some kind of data about the soil behind my house. (Or is it dirt? I don&amp;#x27;t know what I&amp;#x27;m getting into).&lt;p&gt;In 2024 I tried growing some corn. It never sprouted.&lt;p&gt;In 2025 I tried growing some corn. It sprouted and a few ears had enough kernels to make one full mouthful. Tasty, but maybe 7 calories of food for a year of effort.&lt;p&gt;So in 2026 I&amp;#x27;d like to grow: one entire fully formed ear of sweet corn. Anything else is a bonus.&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#x27;s what I wanna develop in 2026 - learning how soil works enough to make it make a thing.  Small moves, Ellie.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 223 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; meridion&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385197"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>223</hn_points><hn_author>meridion</hn_author><hn_order>43</hn_order></item><item><title>MiniMax M2.1: Built for Real-World Complex Tasks, Multi-Language Programming</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388213</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388213</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 01:02:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.minimaxi.com/news/minimax-m21"&gt;www.minimaxi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;ve played with this a bit and it&amp;#x27;s ok. I&amp;#x27;d place it somewhere around sonnet 4.5 level, probably below. But with this aggressive pricing you can just run 3 copies to do the same thing, choose the one that succeeded and still come out way ahead with the cost. Not as great as following instructions as Claude models and can get lost, but still &amp;quot;good enough&amp;quot;.&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#x27;m very happy with using it to just &amp;quot;do things&amp;quot;. When doing in depth debugging or a massive plan is needed, I&amp;#x27;d go with something better, but later going through the motions? It works.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 215 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; 110&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388213"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>215</hn_points><hn_author>110</hn_author><hn_order>57</hn_order></item><item><title>The Algebra of Loans in Rust</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357814</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357814</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:25:29 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://nadrieril.github.io/blog/2025/12/21/the-algebra-of-loans-in-rust.html"&gt;nadrieril.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I have what I thought was a broad knowledge base of rust an experience in it over many domains, but I haven&amp;#x27;t heard of most of those. Have been getting by with `&amp;amp;`, and `&amp;amp;mut` only from those tables!&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I think this is one of Rust&amp;#x27;s best features, and I sorely miss it in Python, JS and other languages. They keep me guessing whether a function will mutate the parent structure, or a local copy in those languages!&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I recently posted in another thread here how I just discovered the &amp;#x27;named loop&amp;#x2F;scope feature, and how I thought it was great, but took a while to discover. A reply was along the effect of &amp;quot;That&amp;#x27;s not new; it&amp;#x27;s a common feature&amp;quot;. Maybe I don&amp;#x27;t really know rust, but a dialect of it...&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 214 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; g0xA52A2A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357814"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>214</hn_points><hn_author>g0xA52A2A</hn_author><hn_order>38</hn_order></item><item><title>Show HN: Ez FFmpeg – Video editing in plain English</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46400251</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46400251</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://npmjs.com/package/ezff"&gt;npmjs.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I built a CLI tool that lets you do common video&amp;#x2F;audio operations without remembering ffmpeg syntax.&lt;p&gt;Instead of:
ffmpeg -i video.mp4 -vf &amp;quot;fps=15,scale=480:-1:flags=lanczos&amp;quot; -loop 0 output.gif&lt;p&gt;You write:
  ff convert video.mp4 to gif&lt;p&gt;More examples:
  ff compress video.mp4 to 10mb
  ff trim video.mp4 from 0:30 to 1:00
  ff extract audio from video.mp4
  ff resize video.mp4 to 720p
  ff speed up video.mp4 by 2x
  ff reverse video.mp4&lt;p&gt;There are similar tools that use LLMs (wtffmpeg, llmpeg, ai-ffmpeg-cli), but they require API keys, cost money, and have latency.&lt;p&gt;Ez FFmpeg is different:
  - No AI – just regex pattern matching
  - Instant – no API calls
  - Free – no tokens
  - Offline – works without internet&lt;p&gt;It handles ~20 common operations that cover 90% of what developers actually do with ffmpeg. For edge cases, you still need ffmpeg directly.&lt;p&gt;Interactive mode (just type ff) shows media files in your current folder with typeahead search.&lt;p&gt;npm install -g ezff&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;Days since last ffmpeg CLI wrapper: 0&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#x27;s incredible what lengths people go to to avoid memorizing basic ffmpeg usage. It&amp;#x27;s really not that hard, and the (F.) manual explains the basic concepts fairly well.&lt;p&gt;Now, granted, ffmpeg&amp;#x27;s defaults (reencoding by default and only keeping one stream of each type unless otherwise specified) aren&amp;#x27;t great, which can create some footguns, but as long as you remember to pass `-c copy` by default you should be fine.&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;i&gt;hiding&lt;/i&gt; those footguns is likely to create more harm than it fixes. Case in point: &amp;quot;ff convert video.mkv to mp4&amp;quot; (an extremely common usecase) maps to `ffmpeg -i video.mkv -y video.mp4` here, which does a full reencode (losing quality and wasting time) for what can usually just be a simple remux.&lt;p&gt;Similarly, &amp;quot;ffmpeg extract audio from video.mp4&amp;quot; will unconditionally reencode the audio to mp3, again losing quality. The quality settings are also hardcoded and hidden from the user.&lt;p&gt;I can sympathize with ffmpeg syntax looking complicated at first glance, but the main reason for this is just that multimedia is &lt;i&gt;really complicated&lt;/i&gt; and that some of this complexity is &lt;i&gt;necessary&lt;/i&gt; in order to not make stupid mistakes that lose quality or waste CPU resources. I truly believe that these ffmpeg wrappers that try to make it seem overly simple (at least when it&amp;#x27;s &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; simple, i.e. not even exposing quality settings or differentiating between reencoding and remuxing) are more hurtful than helpful. Not only can they give worse results, but by hiding this complexity from users they also give users the wrong ideas about how multimedia works. &amp;quot;Abstractions&amp;quot; like this are exactly how beliefs like &amp;quot;resolution and quality are the same thing&amp;quot; come to be. I believe the way to go should be &lt;i&gt;educating&lt;/i&gt; users about video formats and proper ffmpeg usage (e.g. with good cheat sheets), not by hiding complexity that really should not be hidden.&lt;p&gt;Edit: Reading through my comment again, I have to apologize for the slightly facetious opening statement, even if I quality it later on. The fact that so many ffmpeg wrappers exists &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; saying something about its apparent difficulty, but as I argue above, a) there are reasons for this (namely, multimedia itself just being complicated), and b) I believe there are good and bad ways to &amp;quot;fix&amp;quot; this, with oversimplified wrappers being more on the &amp;quot;bad&amp;quot; side.&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 205 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; josharsh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46400251"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>205</hn_points><hn_author>josharsh</hn_author><hn_order>1</hn_order></item><item><title>QNX Self-Hosted Developer Desktop</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46398201</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46398201</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 01:16:53 +0000</pubDate><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://devblog.qnx.com/qnx-self-hosted-developer-desktop-initial-release/"&gt;devblog.qnx.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;hr/&gt;
                    &lt;div&gt;&lt;b&gt;Top Comment:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;blockquote style="margin:1.5em 0; padding:1em 1.5em; border-left:4px solid; font-style:italic;"&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;I always liked their original UI - Photon[1][2]. Very lightweight and fast. Also a distinct and consistent style. I understand why they dropped it in favor of Qt and later Web technologies, but it&amp;#x27;s still a big loss.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.qnx.com&amp;#x2F;developers&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;6.5.0SP1.update&amp;#x2F;com.qnx.doc.neutrino_user_guide&amp;#x2F;using_photon.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.qnx.com&amp;#x2F;developers&amp;#x2F;docs&amp;#x2F;6.5.0SP1.update&amp;#x2F;com.qnx....&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.mikecramer.com&amp;#x2F;qnx&amp;#x2F;momentics_nc_docs&amp;#x2F;photon&amp;#x2F;prog_guide&amp;#x2F;about.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.mikecramer.com&amp;#x2F;qnx&amp;#x2F;momentics_nc_docs&amp;#x2F;photon&amp;#x2F;prog...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Points:&lt;/strong&gt; 199 | &lt;strong&gt;Author:&lt;/strong&gt; transpute&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46398201"&gt;View All Comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><hn_points>199</hn_points><hn_author>transpute</hn_author><hn_order>14</hn_order></item></channel></rss>